¬ Localised file for campaign descriptions

{CAESER_IN_GAUL_JULII_TITLE}House of Julii
{CAESER_IN_GAUL_JULII_DESCR}The year is 58 BC.\n\n
Gaius Julius Caesar has been appointed Pro-Consul of Rome and Governor of Cisalpine Gaul. He is responsible for the protection of the 'Friends of Rome'. These are the Gallic tribes who have agreed to be clients of the Republic: they give up their independence, but receive protection and the other benefits of Roman rule.\n\n
The Germanic Helvetii tribe, however, are not friends of Rome nor friends of the Gauls. They have begun to move south west into the lands occupied by the Aedui and Sequani peoples, two of the tribes who look to Rome and Caesar for protection.\n\n 
This is Caesar's chance. In the chaos of a war perhaps all of Gaul could be brought under Roman control. Any general who manages this would gain enormous political prestige at home, perhaps even enough to become master of Rome.\n\n 
This is your chance to match Caesar's achievements. Take the Roman Legions to victory in Gaul! 

{SONS_OF_MARS_JULII_TITLE}The House Of Julii
{SONS_OF_MARS_JULII_DESCR}You are the new leader (pater familias) of a young and upcoming noble (Patrician) family.\n\n
You have been given a military command by the Senate and People of Rome (SPQR) and must help forge a safe, strong and lasting empire in Italy.\n\n
Your first objectives are to repel a barbarian attack, just near Rome, and then move to take control of the town of Tarquinii, to the north west of Rome.\n\n
As your tutor will have told you, It is up to you to "seize the day" (carpe diem). 

{CAESER_IN_GAUL_TITLE}Caesar in Gaul
{SONS_OF_MARS_TITLE}Sons of Mars
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}Imperial Campaign

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 19/08/2004 16:05:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SENATE_TITLE}The Roman Senate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SENATE_DESCR}Warning!\n\n
This faction was never meant to be played and was only included due to popular demand. Play at your own risk...\n\n
Clicking on the Senate offices list button will crash the game. Clicking on the senate tab will also crash the game. Destroying the Senate is obviously impossible, so it might be impossible to win the game...

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_JULII_TITLE}The House of Julii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_JULII_DESCR}Rome is a place where tradition and history count for much. The legends of the city’s founding are important, and the powerful patrician families are directly descended from the first followers of Romulus. These heroic times demanded harsh, decisive action, and this is a tradition that the often-conservative Romans have maintained to this day. The Romans, including the Julii family, are people for whom politics and war are all or nothing affairs.\n\n 
The Fates have not always been kind to the Julii. They are a patrician family but one whose star has not always been in the ascendant. The family’s fortunes have declined and then risen over the centuries, so much so that they may almost be considered vaguely parvenu: upstarts newly arrived to wealth, power and authority. With the loss of position and status in the past, the other powerful factions of Rome look down (if only ever so slightly) on these ‘new men’ of Rome. The Julii have had to adjust to the realities of politics and power, and have cultivated their popularity with the common people. The rule of Rome may lie with the Senate for now, but the Julii know that the people also have a say in government. The Senate and the patrician classes need the plebeians to at least go along with their actions.\n\n 
This populist attitude to the common people puts the Julii at odds with the other great families. Which approach will lead to great power within Rome has still to be decided. The Julii have a commanding position in northern Italy that means they will be in vanguard of any struggle against barbarians. Success there can be translated into political power in Rome itself, as the mob always loves winners...

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCIPII_TITLE}The House of Scipii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCIPII_DESCR}The city of Rome had a violent foundation, one that mirrors much of the political and military infighting that happens between the great families of Rome. Romulus murdered Remus for jumping over the walls of the city, and then named himself King and renamed the city in his own honour. The patrician families of Rome claim descent from the adventurers, exiles and warriors Romulus recruited to help establish his city. The Scipii should be numbered among these ancient bloodlines.\n\n 
They are not, perhaps, of quite the first rank, although this in itself means that they are keen to prove themselves the equal of any other Romans, but they are certainly among the optimates, the aristocracy of the city, and have been for many generations. They are important people, used to the privileges of rank and the usages of power, both to further Rome’s ambitions and that of their own family. They have also produced able politicians and generals - the two go hand-in-hand in Rome, as political success rarely comes without success on the battlefield.\n\n 
They are, however, unusual in a couple of respects for a Roman family of the old ways. Firstly, they are extravagantly wealthy. Wealth is one thing, and this always brings power with it, but their use of wealth has sometimes surprised more conservative Romans (and Romans are nothing if not conservative). The Scipii also have a taste for Greek learning and culture, again something that surprises and concerns the conservative elements. Nevertheless, despite these un-Roman ways, the Scipii have the political skills and military competence to make their family greatest in Rome, and possibly the rulers of the known world. They may only directly control a couple of provinces in Italy and Sicily, but their ambitions are boundless... and realistic.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARTHAGE_TITLE}Carthage
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARTHAGE_DESCR}The beating heart of Carthage is the city itself, a major port and bustling trade hub nestling on the North African coast. Since gaining independence from its Phoenician forbears, it has quickly established a considerable military, naval and trade empire of its own. Holding the same polytheistic beliefs as their ancestors, the Carthaginians worship many gods, chief amongst them Ba’al Hammon, The Ruler Of The Multitudes, and Tanit, the patron goddess of Carthage itself. Many people believe that child sacrifice takes place at their temples.\n\nCarthage is an expansionist trading state with a small indigenous population. As such, the bulk of its armies consist of mercenary units. The core of its land forces, however, are elite Carthaginian citizens known as the Sacred Band and mighty war elephants from the forests of North Africa. Accomplished seamen, their ships are fast and manoeuvrable, with good ramming and missile capabilities.\n\nSince the 6th century BCE, Carthage has enjoyed a commercial treaty with Rome. The nations even fought together during the Pyrrhic War, although this was a marriage of convenience to prevent Greek hegemony of Southern Italy and Sicily. The outcome of that war was perhaps better for Rome; Carthage gained a foothold in Sicily, but Rome achieved dominance over much of the Italian peninsula. Now, tensions run high between these mighty nations…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_TITLE}Ptolemaic Egypt
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_DESCR}Ptolemaic Egypt has close cultural ties to the Hellenistic world, while maintaining many Egyptian traditions. Founded by Ptolemy in 305 BCE following the death of Alexander the Great, it has become a centre of culture and trade under the influence of its Macedonian rulers.\n\nA general under Alexander, Ptolemy was appointed to govern Egypt after his king’s sudden demise. With Alexander’s empire fragmenting, Ptolemy declared his independence, securing Egypt against his power-grabbing rival generals during the Wars of the Successors (322 - 275 BCE).\n\nEmbracing Egyptian religion and customs, the Ptolemies have since made themselves Pharaohs, continuing the long engineering tradition of great temple and monument building. Greek culture and learning are actively encouraged however, and an upper class of Greco-Egyptians has emerged. But things are not always harmonious; with Greek units garrisoned and veterans settling throughout the territory, the privileges of Greek citizens have led to frequent and bloody uprisings by the indigenous people.\n\nThe intermingling of Greek and Egyptian fighting styles provides the Ptolemaic Pharaohs with a military that is both advanced and balanced, yet still honours the role of the champion commander. Making great use of spear and pike, their forces are further diversified with skilled swordsmen, scythed chariots, and more exotic units such as African war elephants. Egypt's position on the Mediterranean Sea also requires a substantial navy to protect its colonial and trade interests.\n\nWhile Alexandria has become a beacon of civilisation and learning, its rulers are power-hungry opportunists. This new dynasty may yet expand its territory and influence further – perhaps to unify the Greek-speaking peoples? Or west, to carry out Alexander's threatened conquest of Carthage?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GAUL_TITLE}Arverni
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GAUL_DESCR}Descended from a long line of Celts, the warlike Arverni are one of the most powerful tribes of central Gaul. Far more than mere barbarian looters and raiders, they have a complex and sophisticated culture and stronghold centred at Gergovia.\n\nRuled by kings and tribal chieftains, but deferent to their druids, there exists a rigid social order amongst the Arverni. Prestige and power come from a man's abilities as a warrior and a leader as much as his lineage.\n\nHeavily dependent on infantry, the Arverni make great use of javelins and the devastating impact of the charge, led by elite warriors such as Naked Fanatics and Chosen Swordsmen. It is by fighting this way that leaders have earned their places: as champions, proving themselves in conflict.\n\nWhile many matters ostensibly fall to the Arverni's kings and chieftains, in reality, much is governed by the will of the druids, including declarations of war or peace. Blending animism with a pantheon of greater, local and lesser household gods, the Celtic religion is one of the key factors uniting the disparate Gallic tribes.\n\nSeemingly unstoppable en masse, Gallic tribes sacked Rome in 390 BCE and terrorised much of the Aegean as recently as 279 BCE, invading Thrace, Macedon and Illyria. Maybe their destiny lies across the sea to Britannia, with all the Celtic tribes united under a single king? Or to the south, to finally put paid to the growing threat from Rome?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GERMANIA_TITLE}Suebi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GERMANIA_DESCR}The Suebi are an indomitable Germanic culture dwelling in the north east of Germania.\n\nHeavily reliant on infantry and ambush tactics, raiding is their predominant form of conflict. Lightly equipped, most warriors make use of the framea, a javelin-like spear, as swords are a rarity. Often unarmoured they carried their rounded, oval or long, hexagonal shields into battle and wore little more than simple cloaks or other garments at times.\n\nHowever, their fighting prowess is legendary and their warriors rightly feared. Even the stoutest centurion would tremble at the sight of a charging band of Berserkers – or feel the icy hand of fear clutching his heart when the sinister, black-painted Night Hunters spring from the forests.\n\nFairly isolationist, Julius Caesar wrote that there was a paucity of trade outside of the Germanic tribes themselves, occurring only if a surplus of loot or slaves were available. To distinguish themselves from their slaves, freemen and warriors wear a form of topknot that has come to be known as a Suebian knot. Their kings, chiefs and champions sport even more elaborate versions of this same hairstyle.\n\nGiven such ostentatious displays, standing out in battle is important. Kings and chiefs, although drawn from elite lineages, are elected, making their continuation of heroic traditions essential in uniting the tribes.\n\nUnder the right leadership, The Suebi have the potential to unite to a single purpose, and Britannia, Gaul, and Iberia could easily be swept away under the weight of their numbers…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MACEDON_TITLE}Kingdom of Macedon
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MACEDON_DESCR}Desperate to reclaim its past glory, Macedon finds itself locked into its pre-Alexandrian borders by the Illyrians, Thracians and Greek city states on all sides.\n\nMacedon is an administration, with the king holding power and governing in the name of the people. This distinction extends to the treasury, fuelled by an economy of agriculture, forestry and the taxation of ports, the exception being the gold and silver mines granted to the king.\n\nMacedon’s armies remain set on the pattern developed by Phillip II and Alexander, focusing primarily on infantry and cavalry, and led by heroic commanders. Little has changed in terms of tactics, technology or siegecraft since the glory days, with a continuation of Alexander’s hoplite reforms and reliance on the famed Companion and Thessalian cavalry.\n\nMacedon is a shadow of what was and, perhaps, the seed of what could be. Can the Macedonian Empire rise again under a new Alexander?


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PONTUS_TITLE}Kingdom of Pontus
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PONTUS_DESCR}A mountainous region bordering the Black Sea, Pontus contains many fertile river valleys and ports upon which its largely agricultural and trade economy is based. This geography and location also dictate a military focus on infantry and warships. However, a mixture of Greek and Persian influences ensures the forces of Pontus are both advanced and reliable. Their bronze-shield pikemen represent a formidable military backbone, and their swift, deadly scythed chariots are rightly feared.\n\nIts prized commodities, and the opportunism of its well-informed rulers, have enabled Pontus to remain one of the strongest Hellenistic states in existence. With connections throughout the ancient world, largely due to control of Black Sea trade and exports of timber, precious metals and valuable steel, Pontic agents are perfectly placed to gather information on their enemies abroad.\n\nOriginally of Persian origin and part of the former satrapy of Cappadocia, Pontus became a client state under Antigonus in 333 BCE, after Alexander swept Darius' empire away. Essentially, Pontus is now a collection of Greek colonies, ruled by a re-emergent Persian dynasty. In 302 BCE, under Mithridates Ktistes (‘The Founder’), it split from the Macedonian empire during the turmoil of the Wars of the Successors. Having successfully repulsed an invasion by Ptolemy of Egypt, Pontus is now poised to expand across Asia Minor, on into mainland Greece and beyond.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SELEUCID_TITLE}Seleucid Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SELEUCID_DESCR}Although eventually embracing many eastern customs, the Seleucids are renowned for their city building and civil engineering, driving Greek colonisation and Hellenization. Furnished with expert cavalry, including cataphracts, horse skirmishers and war elephants, Seleucid armies also sport a solid core of excellent spear and pike infantry provided by a growing number of Greek-speaking colonists.\n\nAs the campaign begins, such measures are a necessity when faced with the continuing threat from their Ptolemaic Egyptian neighbours and upheaval among the Seleucid's satrapies. Ever the opportunists however, the Seleucid kings may yet turn the tables, bringing much of Alexander’s former western empire under their sway.\n\nFounded by Seleucus Nicator, or Seleucus the Victor, at its height the vast Seleucid Empire stretched from western Anatolia as far east as the Indus River. During the turmoil of the Wars of the Successors, the Seleucids were able to claim and expand Alexander the Great’s eastern empire, as well as parts of Asia Minor.\n\nSeleucus sealed his overall victory at the Battle of Ipsus in 301 BCE. Fielding 500 war elephants, gained through negotiating peace on his eastern border with the Emperor Chandragupta Maurya, his forces proved decisive. The territory under his control contained a diverse range of eastern subcultures, which rapidly became Hellenized by the ruling Macedonian elite and a flood of Greek settlers.\n\nDespite a sometimes precarious position at home, the Seleucids now plan to expand. But where? Into Ptolemaic Egypt? Or beyond, to Alexander’s former western empire in Greece and Macedon?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRUTII_TITLE}The House of Brutii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRUTII_DESCR}The founding of Rome is shrouded in legend. Legend has it, for example, that the Romans can trace their ancestry back to Aeneas, the hero who escaped from the sack of Troy. The founding of Rome also involves violence and murder. Viewed in a certain light, much of subsequent Roman history can be seen as a continuation of these aggressive ways. Since this time, the Romans have kept fine traditions of warfare and high-stakes (or even murderous) politics.\n\n 
The Brutii know all about Roman politics. The founding of the Republic of Rome involves them closely, as they have been at the heart of the Republic for centuries and can even claim to have the ‘Father of the Republic’ in their family. Lucius Junius Brutus pretended to be an idiot for years to avoid being killed by Lucius Tarquinius Superbus (Tarquin), the last king of Rome, and then managed to lead his people in expelling the hated king after the rape of Lucrece. Casting aside his idiot persona, he became one of the first praetors, a ruling office of the patrician class established before the consulship. Lucius Junius Brutus even had his own sons executed for plotting to restore the Tarquins to power...that’s power politics played out to the bitter end. 
Membership of the patrician class is what sets the Brutii apart from the other Roman factions. They are counted among the old families of Rome, those related by blood, marriage or adoption to the founders. These are people who have always been important within the social hierarchy, people who would expect to have authority as a matter of course. This is why they now have control of southern Italy. The Brutii would not have expectations of power, however, if they had not been able to deliver the political and military skills that Rome requires. But now, perhaps, with Rome surrounded by enemies within and without, there is a chance to secure ultimate power, to become the new Imperators of a Roman Republic that extends throughout the known world…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PARTHIA_TITLE}Parthia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PARTHIA_DESCR}The ascension to power of Arsaces, leader of the Parni tribe, assured them victory against the Seleucid protectorate of Parthava, who had been weakened in their attempts to break free of Greco-Macedonian rule. Thus began the rise of Parthia, an eastern empire comparable to the Achaemenid dynasty of old and one of the few who came close to matching the power and wealth of Rome.\n\nA confederation of tribes, Parthia is famed for its horses, nomadic horse-archers and heavy cavalry, the latter developing distinctive bronze or iron scaled armour which covers both horse and rider. For its infantry it relies on ethnic Persian/Iranian hillmen, spear and skirmisher units and sometimes mercenaries, armed and drilled in the Seleucid fashion.\n\nBlending Persian, Hellenistic and local cultures, Parthia’s religious practices and philosophies include veneration of both Greek and Iranian Gods, and the practice of Zoroastrianism. Over time, a noble elite has developed, holding key areas of agricultural land upon which the economy is based, while trade via the emerging Silk Road enables its agents to move easily throughout the ancient world.\n\nAs an Eastern faction, Parthia profits from the rich heritage established by the Persian Empire both in its capacity for trade and in its cultural strength. A degree of tolerance for foreign cultures further eases Parthian conquest of new lands, but their Zoroastrian practices mean an aversion to slavery, which is detrimental to both the economy and to public order. In battle, their great marksmanship and mastery of cavalry makes them a force to be reckoned with when fighting on open ground.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ACARNANIA_TITLE}Lacedaemon
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ACARNANIA_DESCR}With every aspect of their lives and society geared towards warfare, Sparta dominated the Greek world and continues to produce arguably the finest soldiers of the Hellenic period. Trained and hardened in the Spartan Agoge and Krypteia, their warriors and leaders are the embodiment of military discipline and virtue.\n\nComposed of The Spartiates (the citizens), The Periokoi (a class of free, non-citizen merchants and traders) and The Helots (a slave class of agricultural labourers), the Lacedaemonian state was an efficient, if brutal, war machine. Where the slaves of Athens enabled its citizens to pursue art and philosophy, the slaves and non-citizens of Sparta enabled their citizens to pursue warrior perfection as soldiers and champions. Few have fought toe-to-toe with the Royal Spartans and lived to tell the tale.\n\nHaving played a prominent role in the Greco-Persian War, including the legendary stand of the 300 at Thermopylae, and after victory in the Peloponnesus, Sparta’s power and dominance only began to wane following their defeat at the Battle of Leuctra, in 371 BCE, during the aftermath of the Corinthian War. They were eventually forced to submit and join the League of Corinth, under Phillip II of Macedon, following the massacre at the Siege of Megalopolis in 331 BCE.\n\nWhat course Sparta will take now is unclear. Historically, it became an ally of Rome during the Punic Wars. Whether it will follow this path, or conquer Alexander’s former territories, reclaiming its former glory, who can say?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GREEK_CITIES_TITLE}Andros
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GREEK_CITIES_DESCR}Andros, perched on the northern edge of the Cyclades, is a rugged island of steep ridges, sacred springs, and ancient stone sanctuaries, whose legacy stretches deep into the mythic and archaic past, its name recalls Andreus, son of the Thessalian river-god Peneus—himself born of Oceanus and Tethys and revered as the father of noble lineages like Hypseus of the Lapiths and Daphne, beloved of Apollo—who is said to have settled the island and founded its first royal line, linking Andros to the heroic age and the divine waters of Thessaly.\n\nIn myth, the island was a favored site of Dionysus, where wine flowed from temple fountains and ecstatic rites echoed through the hills, making Andros a center of spiritual fervor and liberation long before the classical age. Its people claimed descent from autochthonic settlers and river-born heroes, blending native resilience with divine favor, and during the age of the Trojan War, Andros was known to send ships under the broader Aegean coalitions, its warriors quiet but enduring, shaped by the same ancestral currents as the great mainland houses.\n\nBy the archaic period, Andros had grown into a maritime hub, trading with Euboea, Attica, and Ionia, and founding colonies such as Acanthus and Stageira in Thrace, spreading its influence far beyond the Aegean. It resisted Persian conquest during the Ionian Revolt, contributed ships to the Greek cause at Salamis, and endured Athenian control during the Delian League with quiet defiance and spiritual depth. Its sanctuaries to Dionysus and the river gods remained active even as empires rose and fell, and its people held fast to their mythic ancestry and maritime pride. Now, in the age of successor kingdoms and rising leagues, Andros stands firm—a small but storied island, shaped by water, myth, and the will of its people, poised between isolation and alliance, its fate echoing the strength of its springs and the legacy of its founder.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRITANNIA_TITLE}Iceni
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRITANNIA_DESCR}An Iron Age tribe of southern Britain, the Iceni are a proud and fierce people. They inhabit the flatlands, marshes and fens that border the North Sea, south of the Wash. They are practiced raiders, and frequently engage in battle with their tribal neighbours, the Coritani and Atrebates.\n\nThe Iceni principally make use of infantry when at war. Equipped with large oval or sub-rectangular shields and either a sword or spear, their main distinction from the Celtic tribes of the continent is the practice of painting or tattooing their skin, combined with a greater use of slings in battle. Although light cavalry are used, the Iceni and other British tribes are famed for their highly manoeuvrable war-chariots. After harrying the enemy with javelins, warriors dismount and engage in a fashion similar to the Homeric champions.\n\nFar from simple barbarians, the Iceni have established a capital, known as Venta Icenorum, as well as large religious centres. Although based on agriculture, their economy is sophisticated – they even mint their own coins. Their culture, craft and wealth are illustrated in the form of fantastic gold torques and other jewellery worn by their nobles.\n\nThe Iceni are a proud, fierce Celtic people who have the potential for greatness. From their misty, rain soaked heartland, they could forge an empire…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARMENIA_TITLE}Armenia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARMENIA_DESCR}Armenia is familiar with the rise and fall of empires. Until it was conquered by the Medes, Its iron-age Urartu Kingdom was matched only by Assyria in size and power. Reduced to a satrapy, Armenia passed into the hands of the Macedonians, and latterly the Seleucids. But this subjugation had its benefits. Seleucid power eventually declined enough for Armenia to break away and become a sophisticated Hellenistic state in its own right.\n\nMaintaining this freedom while keeping invaders at bay is the final obstacle to Armenia proving worthy of a glorious empire once more!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DACIA_TITLE}Getae
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DACIA_DESCR}The Getae are a tribe settled around the Lower Danube. They differ from other local tribes through their worship of Gebeleizis, who manifests himself through lightning and thunder, and Zalmoxis, who represents immortality. The Getae strongly believe there are no other gods than their own, yet see themselves as constantly at odds with the heavens, even firing arrows at Gebeleizis during heavy storms.\n\nThere is some debate as to whether the Getae and the Dacians were the same peoples, or different tribes united by a common tongue. The Greeks, certainly, first referred to them as the Getae upon their first encounter during the 7th century BCE. Famed for their impressive shock cavalry and hit-and-run raiding tactics, the Getae earned the reputation during their time under the control of the now-weakened Odrysian Kingdom, to whom they provided military services.\n\nLike many others in the region, they also fell victim to the aggressive expansion of the Macedonian king, Alexander the Great, who razed Getae settlements before beginning his Persian expedition. Since the death of Alexander and the breakup of his empire, the Getae have taken advantage of regional instability, using the opportunity to consolidate themselves. Now they stand ready to strike against former rulers and weaker neighbours alike, facing down resistance and returning aggression one hundred-fold!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NUMIDIA_TITLE}Masaesyli
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NUMIDIA_DESCR}Before the kingdom of Numidia was founded its people were divided in two Berber tribes – the Massylii and the Masaesyli. Both groups were skilled warriors, who regularly settled tribal and inter-tribal rivalries through combat. However, the Massylii also had strong relations with Carthage, which is one of the main reasons why the Masaesyli may wish to align themselves with Rome should the opportunity arise. With the right allies, a Masaesyli king could transform his fledgling kingdom into a prospering African power of some note.\n\nOn the other hand, as a powerful, warlike tribe, the Masaesyli are now faced with the opportunity to forge their own destiny, free from interference by the regional superpowers. They might seek to unite with their southern cousins – the Gaetulians – peacefully or through other means, and an expansion to the eastern province of Phazania is also on the cards.\n\nWhichever route they choose, the Masaesyli's chief desire is the union of all the Berber peoples, so that they might build a fortress-nation of fertile north Africa.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCYTHIA_TITLE}Royal Scythia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCYTHIA_DESCR}In their own eyes, the Royal Scythians are better than everyone else. This is not their problem, but a simple truth. All other tribes, even other Scythians, are no better than slaves and deserving of the same level of consideration, which is to say absolutely none: such is the fierceness of their pride.\n\nAccording to legend, all Royal Scythians are descended from Colaxais, the youngest of three brothers, and the one who was given divine golden gifts. The favour of the gods has stayed with his descendants ever since. Golden they might be, but the Royal Scythians can still see that there are rich pickings to be had among the ‘civilized’ folk to the south and west of their steppes.\n\nThe Scythians were regarded as dangerous barbarians by the Greeks and other civilized peoples, and when faced with the crushing charge of the Scythian Royal Horse, few would disagree. The writings of Herodotus explain nearly all of Scythian culture by reference to Greek equivalents, and the Scythian versions are usually found wanting. To be fair, Herodotus was a product of his time and background. Nonetheless, the Scythians do seem to have been uniquely uncompromising in their approach to war and personal violence, and this seems to have added to their aura of dread.\n\nAs a nomadic people, The Scythians are adept raiders, and capable of recruiting troops at a rapid rate from their home province. They are noted for their craftsmanship and the profit this brings, and their skill with the bow is known far and wide. However, their culture lies at odds with that of the Hellenic States, resulting in a lack of common ground in parley.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Lusitani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}The Lusitani lived in Iberia long before Carthage and Rome disturbed the region, and they will remain long after their oppressors have left. They are, like the Suebi, not a single clan but a confederation of smaller tribes, working together for defensive purposes and mutual gain.\n\nThe Lusitani are fierce and agile warriors, suited to guerrilla warfare – making them excellent light infantry mercenaries – and their women are known to fight alongside the men, such is the fierceness of their culture.\n\nOriginating from the Douro valley in what is now Portugal, the Lusitani gradually spread south, eventually reaching and settling on either side of the Tagus river. The Lusitanian pantheon was very diverse, though they primarily worshipped Endovelicus, god of the people's welfare, as their chief deity. Ataegina was also popular, particularly in the south, as the goddess of nature and fertility. Like many other cultures of the time, the Lusitani were known to sacrifice animals in tribute to their gods.\n\nWith the powerful Gallaeci to the north and the Celtici to the south, the Lusitani are in a precarious position. Though there may be prudence in caution, even fraternisation, with the enemy at first, eventually they must be destroyed.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_THRACE_TITLE}Odrysian Kingdom
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_THRACE_DESCR}The Odrysian Kingdom aspires to be something greater than a union of like-minded Thracian tribes. Eschewing the trappings of tribalism, Teres I united many of them following the collapse of Persian ambition in Greece, forming the Odrysian state with himself as king.\n\nDespite the limited scope of Odrysian hegemony - the kingdom is bounded by the Black Sea and the River Danube - they are generally referred to as the 'Kings of Thrace'. Having allied themselves with Athens, the Odrysians spoke Greek and used it as their administrative language. Greek styles also permeated the Odrysian's military culture, its traditional cavalry nobility being augmented by infantry in phalanx formation.\n\nNow that road networks and basic policies have been established, the groundwork is laid for a stable, civilised Thracian society. However, by the beginning of the 3rd century BCE, centralised royal power hasn't overcome tribal politics completely, and the kingdom's territory has effectively shrunk to a third of its original size as separatist tribes have gradually broken away.\n\nThough reduced in stature, the Odrysian Kingdom has survived against the odds. Now, recovering from a period of instability following the death of Alexander the Great, its old enemy Macedon is rising once again. A successful conclusion to its war with Epirus may lead Macedon to attempt the re-conquest of former territory to the north and east, so there is prudence in re-establishing old alliances with the Greek city-states to the south. A united Odrysia could prove more than a match for its aggressive neighbours, and has the potential to conquer the entire region!


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ACHEA_TITLE}Achaean League
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ACHEA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AETOLIA_TITLE}Aetolian League
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AETOLIA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AGYRION_TITLE}Agyrion
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AGYRION_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AKRAGAS_TITLE}Akragas
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AKRAGAS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ATHENS_TITLE}Athens
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ATHENS_DESCR}The model of democracy, Athens controls the prosperous region of Attica and its fleets continue to be a dominant force in the eastern Mediterranean. A centre of culture and philosophy, its dignitaries lead the vanguard of Greek achievement and learning.\n\n
Renowned for its architecture, art and writing, Athens has long been famed for its cultural achievements – from buildings such as the Parthenon, dedicated to Athena the patron of the city, to the plays and works of Aristophanes, Plato, Socrates, and Sophocles. In many ways, Greek culture is defined by Athens.\n\n
Throughout the Greco-Persian and Peloponnesian Wars, the city state remained both fiercely independent and a leading power of the time, but became part of the wider Macedonian Empire following Phillip II’s decisive victory at the Battle of Chaeronea in 338 BCE. Following the death of Alexander the Great, his generals fought over Athens, particularly the heirs of the Antigonid and Ptolemaic dynasties.\n\n
Ever since they were advised by the Oracle at Delphi to put faith in the city's wooden walls during the Persian Wars, Athens’ military focus has long been its navy. However, continuing the traditions of the classical era, its citizens are also expected to contribute both infantry and cavalry to its armies, although mercenary troops now supplement their numbers. With a strong backbone of spear-bearing Hoplite units supported by archers, a fully formed-up Athenian army makes for a formidable sight – and a tough nut to crack.\n\n
Forever influential, Athens has the opportunity to found a third Athenian League, asserting authority over long term allies and adversaries alike, such as Sparta, Thebes and Corinth.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARGOS_TITLE}Argos
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARGOS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BOETIA_TITLE}Boeotian League
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BOETIA_DESCR}Occupying a position of strategic importance on the Gulf of Korinthos, Boiotia has strong frontiers and trade connections across the region.\n\n
Thebai, its predominant city and capital of the Boiotian League, was a religious confederation at first, but is now chiefly concerned with mutual defence. The city’s surprising support of Persia during its second invasion caused Thebai's temporary displacement as the League’s leader, before perceived Athenian imperialism led to its reinstatement by Sparta.\n\n
Ten years of Athenian occupation followed before the Boiotians won their independence at the Battle of Coronea. Despite a negotiated peace, the reformed Boiotian League's enmity towards Athenai continues unabated. Now, the Boiotians are poised to end Athenai's empire-building once and for all!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTION_TITLE}Byzantion
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTION_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TROEZEN_TITLE}Troezen
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TROEZEN_DESCR}Nestled along the Saronic Gulf, Troezen commands a modest yet symbolically potent position in the northeastern Peloponnese. Though not a military powerhouse, its cultural and religious legacy reverberates across Hellas.\n\n
Founded by Pittheus, the pious son of Pelops, Troezen emerged from the union of Hyperea and Antheia—two ancient towns whose names echo in the myths of the heroic age. It was here that Theseus, son of Aethra and heir to Aegeus, proved his divine lineage by lifting the boulder that concealed his father’s sword and sandals.\n\n
Yet Troezen’s legacy is not without sorrow. Within its walls, the tragic tale of Hippolytus unfolded, as Phaedra’s misguided love led to false accusation and divine punishment. In remembrance, young maidens of Troezen would dedicate a lock of hair to Hippolytus before marriage—a ritual that endures in local custom.\n\n
Despite its modest size, Troezen maintains religious significance and a proud martial tradition, especially among its spearmen. The city’s proximity to key naval routes and its enduring mythic heritage make it a quiet but resilient player in the shifting politics of the region.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CORINTH_TITLE}Corinth
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CORINTH_DESCR}Unified under an oligarchical system of government, Korinthos has become rich from trade due to its geographical position, using the wealth to launch public construction projects on a large scale and forge colonies as far afield as Sicily. Following a period of tyranny, it allied with Sparta, fighting to repel the Persian invasions as part of the Hellenic League. Although Korinthos supported the Athenians during the Greco-Persian Wars, Athenai’s backing of the rebel colony of Korkyra in its struggle against Korinthian rule has caused hostilities to break out between the two great cities. A naval confrontation is sure to ensue, so Korinthos will need a strong fleet if it is to deny Athenian naval supremacy. Yet Korinthos’ sizeable citizen army also makes it a dangerous proposition on land, and far more than a mere foil to the expected Spartan battlefield supremacy…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CROTON_TITLE}Croton
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CROTON_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ELIS_TITLE}Elis
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ELIS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EPIRUS_TITLE}Epirus
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EPIRUS_DESCR}Situated on the Adriatic Sea, Epirus is a Greek kingdom formed of numerous small villages and towns, rather than the great cities of the south. An agriculture and fishing-based society, Epirus nevertheless maintains a balanced army on the Alexandrian model, consisting of cavalry, archers, peltasts, pikemen and war elephants. They also make extensive use of mercenaries from throughout the Greek-speaking world.\n\n
With an economy focused on a diverse and scattered agricultural base, most of Epirus' trade is conducted via its fishing ports on the Adriatic Sea. These also provide the basis for its fleets and a means for its dignitaries to travel abroad.\n\n
Ruled by the Molossian Aeacidae dynasty, the kings of Epirus claim descent from Achilles and Deidamea. With close connections to Macedon, through the marriage of the princess Olympias to Phillip II, Epirus prospered under the empire of their son, Alexander the Great. During the Wars of the Successors (322 - 275 BCE), the Epirot throne was reclaimed through the political manoeuvring of King Pyrrhus with the military backing of Ptolemaic Egypt. In 281 BCE, again with Egyptian support, Pyrrhus entered into conflict with Rome to aid the Greek colony of Tarentum. Although a master tactician, his ‘Pyrrhic victories’ have already become synonymous with success at devastating cost.\n\n
Epirus now faces many choices, across the Adriatic Sea is Rome, to the east Macedon, and to the south Sparta. Will they be potential allies, or enemies to conquer?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GORTYN_TITLE}Gortyn
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GORTYN_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KNOSSOS_TITLE}Knossos
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KNOSSOS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KYDONIA_TITLE}Kydonia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KYDONIA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MASSALIA_TITLE}Massalia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MASSALIA_DESCR}The Greeks formed their colony at Massilia around 600 BCE. Coming from Phocaea, they intended to harvest the region’s resources, and conduct trade from Massilia’s natural harbour.\n\n
By the beginning of the 4th century BCE, the former trading post had blossomed into one of the busiest ports in the Mediterranean, its tendrils even reaching up into Gaul along the Rhone and Durance rivers. Massilia is run as an oligarchy, an assembly headed by noble families. The population are a hybrid of Greek settlers, Gallic locals and others pulled to the city by trade.\n\n
Despite a level of cultural integration, some Gallic tribes still see the city as a prize. Carthage, too, wants to control or destroy their trading rival. Both want Massilia’s great wealth for themselves, and will stop at nothing to take it.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MELOS_TITLE}Melos
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MELOS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RHEGION_TITLE}Rhegion
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RHEGION_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RHODES_TITLE}Rhodes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RHODES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SYRACUSE_TITLE}Syracuse
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SYRACUSE_DESCR}Syracuse is no stranger to war, fiercely championing its independence throughout its long, bloody history. A string of tyrannical leaders dominate that history, defending Syracusan sovereignty against fellow Greeks, Carthaginians and threats from within through a series of treacherous and gruelling wars.\n\n
In spite of these trials, it has become renowned throughout the ancient world as a centre for culture and science: as home to a great theatre and inventors such as Archimedes, who resides there currently. Syracuse is also a wealthy state, profiting from its prime position in the central Mediterranean.\n\n
Despite this, there are still those who would see the Syracusans brought to heel; both Rome and Carthage have reasons to mistrust them. Although the tyrant Hiero II aided Carthage against Rome in the opening stages of their first war, he later made peace with the Romans, entering into an alliance that is still in place to this day. However, Rome wishes to extend its domination to the whole of the Italian peninsula, including the island of Sicily on which Syracuse sits. Ultimately, either regional superpower would like to count Syracuse amongst its possessions. And, now that Carthage and Rome are close to war once again, it stands on a precipice between them; will the alliance with Rome hold true, or will Syracuse forge its own destiny?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TARAS_TITLE}Taras
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TARAS_DESCR}Taras is powerful and glorious! Located on the coast of southern Italy, she is the most dominant and ‘civilised’ city in Magna Graecia. Taras has become powerful due to her exploitation of the region’s fertile soil, her strong naval traditions and its population, who are a rich cultural melting pot.\n\n
Tarantian ambitions are clear: control over the Italian Peninsula and the increased prosperity of its people. Surprisingly enough, the major impediment towards achieving these goals is Rome, the major regional power of the peninsula, and one Taras is still at war with following Pyrrhus' withdrawal. The second obstacle appears to be Syracuse, another Greek city-state on the island of Sicily.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_THESSALY_TITLE}Thessaly
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_THESSALY_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CYRENE_TITLE}Cyrenaica
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CYRENE_DESCR}The Kingdom of Cyrene stands as a beacon of Hellenistic civilization in the rugged and diverse land of North Africa. Established by Greek settlers centuries ago, Cyrene has flourished into a prosperous city-state, renowned for its wealth, culture, and intellectual pursuits. Cyrene is home to a vibrant society where Greek and local traditions blend harmoniously.\n\n
As a dominant power in North Africa, Cyrene boasts a formidable military. Its armies are comprised of skilled Greek hoplites, renowned for their disciplined formations and mastery of the phalanx. Cyrene requires this capable military to protect their holdings, as their position is not completely secure.\n\n
The Ptolemaic Egyptians to the east have a massively powerful kingdom that may seek to conquer our lands. The Libyans and Carthaginians to the west may also try to snatch our holdings in order to increase their wealth. The Rhodians to the north may seem a world away, but they too can threaten our lands if they invade us by sea.\n\n
Cyrene must navigate through these potential rivalries and alliances in order to remain a powerful and independent Greek city-state in this foreign land.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CYPRUS_TITLE}Cyprus
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CYPRUS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NEAPOLIS_TITLE}Neapolis
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NEAPOLIS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SINOPE_TITLE}Trapezos
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SINOPE_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MESSENE_TITLE}Sardes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MESSENE_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PERGAMON_TITLE}Pergamon
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PERGAMON_DESCR}Although a minor player up to that point, Pergamon came to prominence during the struggle of Alexander the Great’s Successors for control of his fragmented empire. When Seleucus was murdered shortly after killing Lysimachus, the lieutenant Philaeterus controlled the fortress city, albeit as a protectorate of the Seleucids.\n\n
Gradually, their influence has declined, enabling Philaeterus to lead Pergamon into a new golden age of culture and learning, building an impressive acropolis and a temple to Athena, Pergamon’s patron goddess. However, Pergamon is not yet a kingdom in the truest sense, and the time is right for expansion beyond its current borders. Yet there are new threats to be faced from Galatia, the duplicitous, expansionist Pontus and Cappadocia. Pergamon must be strong to meet these growing threats to its sovereignty; it must show them how a true Successor state survives.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BOSPORUS_TITLE}Bosporan Kingdom
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BOSPORUS_DESCR}The Cimmerian Bosporus has been fought over for its resources and strategic importance for millennia. The adventurous Greeks of Miletus, in Asia Minor, formed several colonies around the Black Sea coast during the 6th and 7th centuries BCE in order to exploit its resources for trade with the wider Greek world.\n\n
By the beginning of the 5th century BCE their government had gravitated from classical Greek democracy to control by a single family. A previous ruler, Satyrus, conquered nearby Greek cities, heralding the birth of the Cimmerian Kingdom, and a dynasty of rulers that endures to this day. Despite this strength, Cimmeria remains under threat from the surrounding nomadic tribes, and from the avaricious gaze of nearby Pontus, whose military strength may yet prove its undoing.\n\n
A truly multicultural society, Cimmeria welcomes foreign peoples into its borders with greater enthusiasm than other states, and its fertile farmlands offer the seed of great profit, in spite of a notoriously corrupt government. With a military composed chiefly of Scythian and Greek unit-types, Cimmeria can offer a swift and unwelcome surprise on the battlefield.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARCADIA_TITLE}Arcadian League
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARCADIA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BACTRIA_TITLE}Bactria
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BACTRIA_DESCR}Bactria is a gateway to trade between east and west, to India, and to the far-off lands of China. It lay in what is modern-day Afghanistan, and Kandahar itself was founded by Alexander the Great.\n\nAs a protectorate of the Seleucid Empire, Bactria is famed as a province of a thousand cities. It was wealthy thanks to those trade routes and the rich agricultural lands of its fertile valleys and plains. The land is home to Greek colonists, Persians and many more peoples, and was once a part of Alexander’s vast empire. Roxana, Alexander’s wife and the mother of his nominal heir who was born after his death, was a Bactrian princess.\n\n
In the confusion of wars that followed Alexander’s death, Seleucus I Nicator established his control over the eastern parts of Alexander’s empire, including Bactria. The region was heavily colonised by Greek settlers, more so than any other part of the east, and was largely Hellenised as a result, with Greek culture and influence paramount in all things. As such, Bactria’s armed forces brought a rich and varied blend of warriors to the field, with hoplites, peltasts, and fierce swordsmen.\n\n
With the Seleucid Empire locked in a series of wars against the other Successor states, Bactria was a satrapy with a degree of independence. During the rule of Diodotus, it has become an entirely independent Hellenistic kingdom. Under their new king, the Bactrians could be a vigorous military power, benefiting hugely from any breakdown in Seleucid authority and inattention from Parthia. Immense wealth, and tough warriors, could take their armies all the way to the shores of the Mediterranean…\n\n
As veterans of the Successor Wars, Hellenic states hold few surprises in battle for the warriors of Bactria. As a result, the Bactrian soldiery faces Hellenic armies with great confidence and courage. Well-situated for trade, they enjoy enhanced commercial and industrial income, and with their popular Hellenic outlook, they find it easier to spread cultural influence with others. However, the edge of the Great Steppe is a troublesome place for a Hellenic culture to settle; Bactria finds it difficult to curry favour with the aggressive nomad tribes.\n\n
Bactria is a land of a thousand golden cities all grown rich on trade, and sits at the crossroads between the Hellenistic and Indian worlds, and “Serica”, the lands of silk, to the east. With the Seleucids struggling against Ptolemaic Egypt, the Bactrians could establish their own empire stretching from the roof of the world to, possibly, the far shores of the Mediterranean.



{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ALLOBROGES_TITLE}Allobroges
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ALLOBROGES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BOII_TITLE}Boii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BOII_DESCR}A Celtic tribe, the Boii were fierce warriors and, at least originally, semi-nomadic herders. Their name itself derives from either the word for ‘warrior’ or ‘cow’, thus making them the ‘warrior people’ or ‘herding people’.\n\n
Although their exact origins remain unclear, by 390 BCE the Boii had taken part in the Celtic incursions into northern Italy. Moving south, over the Alps, they drove back the Etruscans and occupied their territory. At the same time, on the other side of the Alps, they also moved east, into modern day Eastern Germany and Bohemia, itself named for the tribe which settled there.\n\n
Leading a frugal lifestyle, Boii society was geared towards warfare and agriculture, their most prized commodities being gold and livestock. Status amongst their leaders was judged not only through military prowess, but the amount of cattle owned and retinue supported. Historically, the Boii allied with the other tribes of Cisalpine Gaul and the Etruscans against the rapidly-expanding Roman Republic. Defeated and driven back, in later years some of the tribe joined the Helvetii in the migration that sparked Caesar’s Gallic Wars, and later supported Vercingetorix at the Battle of Alesia.\n\n
In the east, their territories eventually fell to the Dacians. From their current central European position however, the Boii are well placed to strike south into either Italy or Greece, west into Gaul, or east against the Dacian tribes.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARNI_TITLE}Carni
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARNI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CENOMANNI_TITLE}Cenomanni
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CENOMANNI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_INSUBRES_TITLE}Insubres
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_INSUBRES_DESCR}The Insubres are wise and ancient. They arrived in Italy long ago and settled in its northwestern part. Their former neighbours, the Etruscans, are probably the most influential civilisation in this part of the world, and the communication between them has proved highly beneficial for the Insubres. They have adopted some Etruscan cultural and military traditions and raised their prestige and prosperity as a result. A trade in natural resources and slaves was established early on, and became the basis for growth, both economic and cultural. Another strong influence came from the Greeks, who have been trading with Gallic people for centuries.\n\n
The Insubres’ ambitions are focused on providing a safe, bright future for everyone in the community. Their long coexistence with other cultures has contributed strongly to their affinity for and expertise in diplomacy, and as trade or military partners. To persevere, the Insubres must overcome the ambitions and desires of their neighbours, both close and distant.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LEPONTI_TITLE}Lepontii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LEPONTI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LIGURES_TITLE}Ligures
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LIGURES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SENONES_TITLE}Senones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SENONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RAETI_TITLE}Raeti
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RAETI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DAUNIANS_TITLE}Daunians
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DAUNIANS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MESSAPIANS_TITLE}Messapians
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MESSAPIANS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PEUCITANS_TITLE}Peucetians
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PEUCITANS_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENETI_TITLE}Veneti
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENETI_DESCR}The Veneti are a cultured, polished people. Their ancient lands are situated in the northeast of Italy. The time of the Veneti’s arrival here is shrouded in the mists of the distant past. There are legends and stories of course, but nobody can say with certainty where their true origins lie. The Veneti people see themselves closest to the Italian tribes, yet there is also Gallic blood in their veins, which makes them unique among Italian peoples.\n\n
Their strength lies in the high fertility of their lands, their advanced naval technology and their excellent, progressive command of the ways of animal husbandry. The Veneti are probably most famous for their superior horses, and by extension, superior cavalry.\n\n
Their ambitions are all concerned with control of northern Italy. Given the choice, they would prefer a peaceful existence of hard work and cultural eminence. Given the ambitions of their neighbours, however, this seems too difficult a thing to achieve!



{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARITIM_TITLE}Aritim
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARITIM_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FELATHRI_TITLE}Felathri
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FELATHRI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRENTANI_TITLE}Frentani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRENTANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LUCANI_TITLE}Lucani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LUCANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PICENTES_TITLE}Picentes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PICENTES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SABINES_TITLE}Sabines
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SABINES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAMNITES_TITLE}Samnites
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAMNITES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TARCHUNA_TITLE}Tarchuna
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TARCHUNA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_UMBRI_TITLE}Umbri
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_UMBRI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VEII_TITLE}Veii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VEII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VIESUL_TITLE}Viesul
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VIESUL_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VOLSCI_TITLE}Volsci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VOLSCI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ALERIA_TITLE}Aleria
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ALERIA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAMERTINES_TITLE}Marmetines
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAMERTINES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HISTRI_TITLE}Histri
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HISTRI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER



{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AEDUI_TITLE}Aedui
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AEDUI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CAVARI_TITLE}Ausci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CAVARI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BITURIGES_TITLE}Bituriges
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BITURIGES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CADURCI_TITLE}Cadurci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CADURCI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARNUTES_TITLE}Carnutes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARNUTES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ERAVISCI_TITLE}Eravisci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ERAVISCI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GALATIA_TITLE}Galatia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GALATIA_DESCR}Celts of Gallic descent, the Galatians came to settle in and dominate areas of central Anatolia and Phrygia. Proud warriors, famed for their skill, loyalty, and ferocity in battle, they were highly prized as mercenaries throughout the Hellenistic world. It was 300 Galatian warriors that Julius Caesar gifted Cleopatra in 48 BCE as her bodyguard, such was their fearsome reputation.\n\n
Comprised of three tribes, the Tectosages, Tolistobogii, and Trocmi, the Galatians splintered off from Brennus’ Gauls during their invasion of Macedon and Greece in 279 BCE. Moving first through Thrace, they crossed the Bosporus into Asia Minor as allies of Nicomedes of Bithynia, in exchange for defeating his brother in their dynastic quarrel. After joining Nicomedes in a brief struggle against the expansionist Seleucids, they settled the area that would eventually become known as Galatia. The territory was divided between the three tribes, each maintaining its own capital and rule, but coming together in council at Drynemeton, a sacred grove of oaks situated southwest of Ancyra, the Tectosages’ capital. Leaving the indigenous Cappadocians relative control of their own lands in exchange for tithes, the Galatians became a military aristocracy. Much like the Spartans, this enabled them to focus on their martial skills. Fighting in the Celtic style, they made deadly use of swords, javelins, and oval shields.\n\n
Situated at the heart of Asia Minor, the Galatians have many choices before them. Extend their control over Cappadocia, or strike for the sea, through Pontus, Pergamon, or Bithynia and, with their position consolidated, sweep either east or west…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HELVETII_TITLE}Helvetii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HELVETII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LEMOVICES_TITLE}Lemovices
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LEMOVICES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LEXOVII_TITLE}Lexovii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LEXOVII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MANDUBII_TITLE}Mandubii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MANDUBII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NAMNETES_TITLE}Namnetes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NAMNETES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORI_TITLE}Nori
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_OSISMII_TITLE}Osismii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_OSISMII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PICTONES_TITLE}Pictones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PICTONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LINGONES_TITLE}Raurici
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LINGONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_REDONES_TITLE}Redones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_REDONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUTENI_TITLE}Ruteni
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUTENI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SANTONES_TITLE}Santones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SANTONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCORDISCI_TITLE}Scordisci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCORDISCI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SEQUANI_TITLE}Sequani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SEQUANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ELUSATES_TITLE}Sotiates
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ELUSATES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TARBELLI_TITLE}Tarbelli
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TARBELLI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TRIBALLI_TITLE}Triballi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TRIBALLI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SEGUSIAVI_TITLE}Tulingi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SEGUSIAVI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURONES_TITLE}Turones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_UNELLI_TITLE}Unelli
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_UNELLI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENETI_GAUL_TITLE}Veneti
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENETI_GAUL_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VINDELICI_TITLE}Vindelici
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VINDELICI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VIVISCI_TITLE}Vivisci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VIVISCI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VOCONTII_TITLE}Vocontii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VOCONTII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VOLCAE_TITLE}Volcae
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VOLCAE_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MARCOMANNI_TITLE}Marcomanni
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MARCOMANNI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HELISII_TITLE}Lugii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HELISII_DESCR}In the expansive lands of eastern Germania, the Lugii confederation emerges as a formidable alliance, its core composed of the Nahanarvali, Helveconae, Buri, and Harii tribes. Nestled in what is now modern-day Poland, this coalition represents a mosaic of diverse strengths and identities.\n\n
The Lugii, central to this confederation, seamlessly blend guerrilla tactics from the Nahanarvali with the disciplined martial traditions of the Helveconae. The Buri, skilled in trade and diplomacy, contribute to the alliance's prosperity, while the fierce warriors of the Harii infuse an unwavering spirit into the collective.\n\n
Under a shared purpose, the Lugii and their protectorate tribes employ a versatile approach to conflict, encompassing raiding, ambushes, and hit-and-run tactics. Distinctive in appearance and armed with diverse weaponry, the warriors project an image of unity amidst diversity.\n\n
Leadership within the Lugii places emphasis on a balance of strength and strategic acumen. As protectorates in the intricate web of eastern Germanic tribes, the Lugii confederation and its associated tribes embark on separate but intertwined journeys, navigating a shared saga and leaving an indelible mark on the unfolding narrative of this era.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAXONS_TITLE}Saxoni
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAXONS_DESCR}First mentioned in Ptolemy's ‘Geographia’, the Saxons were a Germanic people who lived near the North Sea coast. While many similar peoples migrated southward, they mostly remained in the north, raiding and settling across the lands bordering the North Sea.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ATREBATES_TITLE}Atrebartes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ATREBATES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BELGAE_TITLE}Belgae
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BELGAE_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BELLOVACI_TITLE}Bellovaci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BELLOVACI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EBURONES_TITLE}Eburones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EBURONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MEDIOMATRICI_TITLE}Mediomatrici
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MEDIOMATRICI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MORINI_TITLE}Morini
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MORINI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PARISII_TITLE}Parisii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PARISII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_REMI_TITLE}Remi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_REMI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SUESSIONES_TITLE}Suessiones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SUESSIONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TREVERII_TITLE}Treverii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TREVERII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NERVII_TITLE}Nervii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NERVII_DESCR}A Celto-Germanic people, the Nervii were the most fierce – and fearless – of the Belgae tribes inhabiting northern Gaul, and renowned for their courage.\n\n
At the Battle of Sabis in 57 BCE, where their surprise attack almost defeated Caesar’s legions, they fought until only 500 of their original 60,000 warriors remained. Such bravery was at the heart of their culture, which was Spartan-like in both outlook and reputation. The Nervii would eschew all luxury, especially alcohol, which they perceived made the body and spirit weak. Instead, they pursued the traditions of their Celtic and Germanic origins, venerating the cult of the hero-warrior. As such, their kings and chieftains were chosen due to their martial prowess and wise leadership.\n\n
With such great emphasis placed on an individual’s skill and bravery in battle, the Nervii rarely used cavalry and missile weapons, apart from javelin-like lances. They instead favoured ambushes and lightning assaults to close quickly with their enemy and prove their mettle.\n\n
They are in a good position to conquer the neighboring belgic tribes, and push deeper into Gaul. In fact, their fearsome reputation and skill in battle makes Nervii expansion further to the east or south highly probable…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRIGANTES_TITLE}Brigantes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BRIGANTES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CALEDONIA_TITLE}Caledonii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CALEDONIA_DESCR}The Caledonii were a confederation of northern British tribes, banding together as an enemy of the Roman invaders. Tacitus described them as burly, red-haired northmen with long limbs; furious and barbaric. They battled the Roman invaders on many occasions and were never truly conquered, even pushing the Romans back to Hadrian's Wall before an accord was made.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CANTIACI_TITLE}Cantiaci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CANTIACI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CORIELTAUVI_TITLE}Corieltauvi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CORIELTAUVI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EBLANI_TITLE}Ebdani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EBLANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DEMETAE_TITLE}Demetae
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DEMETAE_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DUMNONII_TITLE}Dumnonii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DUMNONII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEION_TITLE}Teion
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEION_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ASTURES_TITLE}Astures
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ASTURES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BASTETANI_TITLE}Bastetani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BASTETANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CANTABRI_TITLE}Cantabri
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CANTABRI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARPETANI_TITLE}Carpetani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CARPETANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CELTICI_TITLE}Celtici
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CELTICI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CESSETANI_TITLE}Cessetani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CESSETANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EDETANI_TITLE}Edetani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EDETANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GALLAECI_TITLE}Gallaeci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GALLAECI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ILERCAVONES_TITLE}Ilercavones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ILERCAVONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ILERGETES_TITLE}Ilergetes
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ILERGETES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CELTIBERIA_TITLE}Celtiberi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CELTIBERIA_DESCR}The Celtiberians are a warlike people. From their Celtic origins in northern central Iberia, the Celtiberian tribes united into a confederation, and they have expanded east and southwest through migration and conquest, displacing a number of other tribes in the process.\n\nTheir capital is Numantia, east of the great 'Meseta Central' plateau that runs through the heart of Iberia. The region's topography lends itself to the mass 'transhumance', or livestock migration, to the grassy lowlands of the Ebro valley, which provides the Celtiberi's chief food supply. Chiefly a militaristic society, they also hold the rite of 'excarnation', the practice of leaving dead warriors' bodies on their funeral litters so flesh and organs can be stripped by vultures.\n\nBy the middle of the 3rd century BCE, Roman and Carthaginian expansionism has brought both to the Celtiberi's door. This places difficult choices before them; both superpowers have interfered in Iberia for far too long, yet it is not possible to take on Rome and Carthage at the same time, despite the Celtiberi's knowledge of the terrain, their superb fighting prowess, and alliances with other tribal peoples. For now, they maintain their neutrality, but it cannot last. Someone must control the Iberian peninsula, could it be the Celtiberi?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ORETANI_TITLE}Oretani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ORETANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURDETANI_TITLE}Turdetani
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURDETANI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VACCAEI_TITLE}Vaccaei
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VACCAEI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VASCONES_TITLE}Vascones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VASCONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VETTONES_TITLE}Vettones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VETTONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BALARI_TITLE}Balari
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BALARI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CORSI_TITLE}Corsi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CORSI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IOLEI_TITLE}Sardi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IOLEI_DESCR}The Sardi are a brave, hard people, with a strong connection to their homeland. Being islanders, they view their home as a vessel which carries and nurtures their kin along on the waves of life and destiny. It is the duty of every warrior, every stateman – every member of their society – to cherish and protect their homeland and its many treasures. In return, Sardinia provides generous supplies of natural resources, wildlife, fertile soil and seafood in its coastal waters.\n\n
The greatest source of potential peril to the Sardi is Carthage - one of the most powerful forces in the entire region, which dominates the waters, certain coastal parts of Sardinia and many of the nearby land masses. No one, however, has even the slimmest of chances to tame Sardinia – the Sardi are her only masters.



{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GAETULI_TITLE}Gaetuli
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GAETULI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GARAMANTES_TITLE}Garamantia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GARAMANTES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LIBYA_TITLE}Libya
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LIBYA_DESCR}The tribes of Libya have been under Carthaginian rule and influence for centuries. The region of Tripolitania is an important trade hub that has greatly contributed to Carthage's control of the Mediterranean, and the Libyan desert has provided them with strong warriors in the form of mercenaries to defend their holdings.\n\n
For a time, the people of Libya were content with this arrangement, but now may be the time for them to expel their Phoenician overlords from the continent...

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MASSYLII_TITLE}Massylii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MASSYLII_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAURI_TITLE}Mauri
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAURI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NASAMONES_TITLE}Nasamones
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NASAMONES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GERRHA_TITLE}Gerrha
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GERRHA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MINAEA_TITLE}Ma'in
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MINAEA_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NABATAEA_TITLE}Nabataea
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NABATAEA_DESCR}A civilisation of great builders who pioneered many construction techniques, the Nabataeans were the first to use cement extensively and build remarkable watertight reservoirs to ensure they always had the necessary supplies. They were also very literate and progressive people, who had remarkable gender equality considering the times in which they lived, even allowing women to participate in their political and religious life. Even if the Nabataeans were often threatened, as they were by powerful foes such as the Seleucids and Judeans, their progressive society allowed them to flourish and prosper.\n\nN
abataea is an important crossroads for the spice trade, serving as a conduit between the southern kingdoms that produced frankincense and myrrh and the wealthy eastern and western empires who were the primary buyers. Of course, preserving all this wealth at such a strategically important geographical location makes it essential that the Nabataeans maintain an army of well-trained troops and a strong navy. They have reinforced their excellent armed forces with their ability to adapt their environment to best advantage, making the capital of Petra an impregnable city as a result.\n\n
Positioned on a strategic chokepoint between two strong empires, Egypt and the hostile Seleucids, has been quite challenging for the Nabateans; they could take a risk and seek a military resolution to the conflict with their rich Seleucid enemies or take the long road - solidifying their position before seeking expansion to the south, where the other, less organised Arabian tribes dwell, just waiting to be absorbed!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_QEDAR_TITLE}Qidri
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_QEDAR_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_COLCHIS_TITLE}Colchis
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_COLCHIS_DESCR}Far to the east of the Black Sea, at the very edge of the Greek world, lies Colchis. A place of legend, it is said to have been the final destination on Jason’s quest for the Golden Fleece.\n\n
Colchis profits well from its position as a crossroads for many trade-routes, and other cultures are welcomed into it its lands. In fact, it has assimilated much of Eastern culture into both its civilian and its military, making for a unique hybrid of skills on the battlefields.\n\n
Around the 6th century BCE, Greek traders from Militus arrived to construct a thriving mercantile economy from this former Persian satrapy. Its current ruler controls a powerful Greek trading state with strong Scythian influences and a nobility who extol the finest qualities of both cultures. His warriors fight in the Greek fashion, yet the ferocity of their nomadic past is very much alive. As such, Colchis has set out to conquer much of the land around it - to absorb further Scythian tribes, and as many former-Persian lands as possible, into his burgeoning empire.


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARDIAEI_TITLE}Ardiaei
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARDIAEI_DESCR}The Illyrian tribe of the Ardiaei originated inland, but eventually found their way to the Adriatic coast and settled there, dedicating themselves to sea-born piracy of the Adriatic Sea trade routes. Seen as debauched by the Greeks from whom they have borrowed aspects of their culture, they drink heavily and celebrate greatly in the plunder stolen from their enemies.\n\n
Perhaps most famously, The Kingdom of Ardiaei briefly became a powerful nation under the leadership of Agron, who captured several Greek cities and constantly raided the Adriatic coast. He also lent his services to the Acarnanians when the Epirot monarchy was extinguished, achieving his greatest victory in their defence.\n\n
After Agron's sudden, potentially alcohol-related death, his widow Teuta has become de facto ruler of the Ardiaei. However, she has inherited a kingdom whose continual piracy is now drawing the ire of powerful forces in the region – those with a vested interest in the profits of Adriatic trade, like Rome.\n\n
As the 3rd century BCE begins the Ardiaei have a fight ahead of them. However, they have strength and cunning that their neighbours lack; can they turn it to their advantage and bring first the Adriatic, and maybe the world, under Ardiaei control?

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BASTARNAE_TITLE}Bastarnae
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BASTARNAE_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_APULI_TITLE}Apulii
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_APULI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BREUCI_TITLE}Breuci
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BREUCI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DAORSI_TITLE}Daorsi
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DAORSI_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DELMATAE_TITLE}Delmatae
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DELMATAE_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IAZYGES_TITLE}Iazyges
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IAZYGES_DESCR}PLACEHOLDER

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TYLIS_TITLE}Tylis
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TYLIS_DESCR}Tylis is the product of chaos; one of several breakaway groups from Brennus' great horde of Celts who invaded Greek territory from the north-western forests at the beginning of the 3rd century BCE. At this time, Greece was in the throes of the bitter struggles between the successors of Alexander the Great. It was into this madness that the forebears of Tylis descended, swarming over the army of Ptolemy Keraunos and killing him in battle.\n\n
Ptolemy was the king of the powerful state of Macedon and so, with his death, the region fell into anarchy. The Celts took advantage of this chaos, ravaging Macedon and attempting to make further gains to the south. It was the combined might of Antigonus II and the Aetolian League that finally pushed them back, defeating the Celtic army at Thermopylae, Delphi and finally Lysimachia in 277 BCE.\n\n
Following these defeats the remaining Celts retreated, migrating further east and settling in north eastern Thrace - finally basing themselves at Tylis, near the Black Sea coast, an ideal location from which to raid the surrounding areas for food and riches. However, others have chosen not to settle, crossing onto the Anatolian peninsula to fight as mercenaries there.\n\n
Now, the position Tylis finds itself in is extremely fragile. All around it are highly-aggressive Thracian tribes who must be shown that their new Celtic neighbours are here to stay!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ROMANS_UNIFIED_TITLE}The Roman Republic
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ROMANS_UNIFIED_DESCR}The Roman Republic is in a period of major growth, and the burgeoning Republic boasts the military muscle to match its ambition. Rome is the dominant power on the Italian peninsula, and stands at a turning point in history. But to expand, she must conquer. To the North lie the Barbarian lands. To the east, the Greeks. To the South, the Greeks in Taras and their Epirote allies have yet to be driven from the shores of Italy. Further south and west, the Carthaginians…\n\nSince throwing off the rule of the Etruscan Kings in around 500 BCE, the Roman Republic has come to represent a power like no other. Military service is mandatory for citizens, and one of the most profound contributions a citizen can make. This makes the Republic militaristic at its very heart.\n\nThe strength of the Roman army lies in organisation, discipline and strict tactical doctrine. Well-drilled, well-equipped heavy infantry form the backbone of the army. The young, lightly armoured hastati man the frontlines. Behind them stand the more skilled, chainmail-clad principes. The oldest and most experienced warriors – the bronze-armoured triarii – hold the rear. These monolithic formations are supported by the Roman cavalry, or equites.\n\nSurrounded by rivals and potential enemies, Rome faces challenges at every turn. He who rules in Rome can rule the world, but only through the glory of conquest!

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_INDIA_TITLE}The Maurya Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_INDIA_DESCR}The Maurya Empire is the greatest power in India, born from the conquests of Chandragupta Maurya who united the north and drove back both native rivals and foreign invaders. His alliance with Seleucus secured the western provinces and left the Mauryas dominant from the Punjab to the Ganges Valley.\n\n
Now under his son, Bindusara, the empire has turned its gaze southward. The fertile lands of the Deccan are being brought under Mauryan control, while governors and officials enforce the king’s authority over distant provinces. Trade, agriculture, and a strong bureaucracy provide the wealth needed to maintain such vast domains.\n\n
Yet the empire is far from secure. Its provinces are diverse and restive, and the loyalty of distant rulers is not guaranteed. Enemies lie beyond its frontiers, while within, ambition and rebellion may yet test the dynasty. The Mauryas have the chance to create an enduring dominion, but only if strength, order, and unity can be maintained.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CHOLA_TITLE}Chola
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CHOLA_DESCR}The Cholas rule from the fertile plains of southern India, where the Kaveri River sustains a prosperous land. Their dynasty is ancient, with roots stretching back centuries, and their kings have long fought to dominate the Tamil country.\n\n
The Cholas are famed for their strong administration and for the irrigation works that bring wealth to their fields. Yet they share the south with two other great powers, the Cheras and the Pandyas, and the rivalry of these three crowned kings is fierce and unending.\n\n
The Cholas are ambitious rulers who look beyond their homeland. With strength on land and mastery of the seas, they have the chance to outshine their rivals and build a realm to rival any in the known world.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ANURADHAPURA_TITLE}Anuradhapura
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ANURADHAPURA_DESCR}The kingdom of Anuradhapura lies in the heart of Sri Lanka, a land of fertile plains and sacred places. From their capital city, the kings of Anuradhapura claim the island’s throne and the loyalty of its people.\n\n
The kingdom is renowned for its great irrigation works that tame the dry lands, and for its devotion to the new faith of Buddhism. Temples, stupas, and monasteries rise as symbols of piety and of royal power.\n\n
Yet the island is never free from strife. Invaders from the mainland and rivals at home threaten the throne, but the kings of Anuradhapura are proud and unyielding. With their blessings and their strength, the kingdom can endure and prosper.

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MASSAGETAE_TITLE}Massagetae
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MASSAGETAE_DESCR}The Massagetae are a fierce nomad tribe with a long history of destroying civilized armies, as their utter crushing of Cyrus the Great and his Persian army attests. From their steppe homeland, they have the power to sweep down on nomad and settled enemies alike, taking what they will and moving swiftly on to new victories and new conquests. By using their strengths as horsemen, there is little they cannot achieve.\n\n
Historically, there is a good chance Herodotus was confused about the identities of the various steppe peoples. While he used the term Massagetae to describe these people, a word that translates as 'great Getae', the original Getae were a Dacian tribe, not Scythian or nomadic. Herodotus also described them as living beyond the Caspian Sea. He did, however, say that they resembled the Scythians but with their own customs and practices. In particular, he mentions strange funeral rites that involve cooking and eating important men who die honourably. Quite sensibly, any who died of horrid diseases were not eaten…

{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ETRUSCANS_TITLE}Etruscan League
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ETRUSCANS_DESCR}The Etruscan League, reduced to one major center in Velzna, is a shadow of what it once was. Despite this, the Etruscans still shine with cultural, religious and industrious prominence which can only be matched by the old and highly-respected Greek city states. Being in a league of their own, the Etruscan cities are rival peers first and loving siblings second.\n\n
The League's ambitions are to maintain the favourable status quo in the region - one which predominantly benefits her own people. There are, however, powers with opposing interests and desires of their own. Rome is growing powerful and menacing every day, having already taken much of the Etruscans' land. Control of the sea is claimed by both the Romans and Carthaginians. With an intelligent approach and divine help, however, the league will both prevail and prosper!


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SABA_TITLE}Saba
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SABA_DESCR}The Kingdom of Sheba—or Saba—stands in the rugged highlands of southern Arabia, its lifeblood the fertile lands sustained by the monumental Maʾrib Dam. This ancient marvel channels seasonal waters into lush fields, fueling a realm of wealth and stability.\n\nAt its height from roughly the 8th century BCE to the 3rd century CE, Sheba ruled over southern Arabia, its prosperity built on the trade of frankincense, myrrh, spices, and precious goods along the lucrative Incense Routes. Caravans passed through Sabaean lands, connecting Asia, Africa, and the Mediterranean—and filling royal coffers with treasure.\n\n
The Sabaeans worship the moon god Almaqah and are ruled by priest-kings known as mukarribs, who hold both spiritual and temporal authority. Their cities—Marib and Sirwah—are built of stone, adorned with temples and inscriptions, symbols of power and faith.\n\n
Yet Sheba’s reign is not eternal. Rival kingdoms like Hadhramaut, Qataban, and Ma’in vie for control of the incense trade, and internal struggles threaten its unity. As the Himyarites rise, Sheba must defend its wealth and legacy, lest the dam that sustains its land—and its power—fail.


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KUSH_TITLE}Kush
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KUSH_DESCR}The Kingdom of Kush rises in the lands south of Egypt, centered on Nubia’s Nile Valley. Once ruled from Napata, its monarchs seized Upper Egypt in the 8th century BC and reigned as Egypt’s 25th Dynasty—until Assyrian steel forced them to retreat and shift their power south to Meroe.\n\n
Now based at Meroe, Kush is a fortress of iron and independence. Its lands are rich with iron ore and timber, forged into weapons, tools, and wealth. Towering pyramids rise at its necropolises, symbols of a kingdom both noble and unbowed.\n\n
Kush stands apart with a distinct culture—a blend of Egyptian influence and its own traditions. Its rulers worship their own gods, write in the unique Meroitic script, and shape a society resilient and proud.\n\n
Ever vigilant, the Kushites defend Nubia from foes to the north and south. With iron in their hands and pyramids at their backs, they have the potential to reclaim past glory or forge new legacies under the burning sun of the Nile.


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ILLYRIA_TITLE}Illyrians
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ILLYRIA_DESCR}The tribes of the mountainous region of Illyria are made up of proud warriors who have mostly been able to retain their independence from foreign overlords. However, the Macedonians under Philip II, and later Alexander the Great, have defeated the Illyrians on many occasions and have occupied their lands for some time. Still, the Illyrians were never fully integrated into the Macedonian empire, and once it fell, Illyria slipped away from their grasp once more.\n\n
Illyria, positioned east of the Adriatic Sea, is surrounded by many dangers. Alexander the Great's empire may have fallen, but the Macedonians are still a dangerous force that have a strong grip over Greece. Epirus, the Ardiaei, and other barbarian tribes may also prove to be a threat. However, the Romans may prove to be the greatest danger to Illyria's existence, as their legions are just a single voyage across the Adriatic away. The tribes of Illyria must unite to face these great perils.


{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAKA_TITLE}Sakas
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAKA_DESCR}The Saka people, hailing from the vast Central Asian steppes, are fearless warriors mounted on horseback. Their nomadic lifestyle and deep warrior tradition have made them renowned conquerors, adapting and absorbing the cultures they encounter. With unmatched skill in mounted archery, they strike swiftly and relentlessly, driven by their ambition to expand their dominion across the Eastern world.\n\n
The Saka crave conquest and the expansion of their dominion. They perceive neighboring empires as tempting prizes, viewing them as stepping stones to greatness. The allure of riches and the glory of victory drive them forward, propelling their relentless ambition.\n\n
The Saka are not bound by borders or constrained by settled societies; they are free spirits, seeking to carve their own destiny across the Eastern world. They will not stop their conquests until they can celebrate the ruin of the civilized world!



{BIGGEST_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}Biggest Campaign (WIP)

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 19/08/2004 16:05:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

