¬ Localisation file for transition screen quotes
¬ Lines in brackets are not to be translated

{Quote_1}
I think the slain care little if they sleep or rise again.
{Quote_2}
A people's voice is dangerous when charged with wrath.
{Quote_3}
Victory loves prudence.
{Quote_4}
Against danger it pays to be prepared.
{Quote_5}
Brave men are a city's strongest tower of defence.
{Quote_6}
It is the noblest and safest thing for a great army to be visibly animated by one spirit.
{Quote_7}
Ah! The generals! They are numerous but not good for much!
{Quote_8}
War, as the saying goes, is full of false alarms.
{Quote_9}
War gives the right of the conquerors to impose any conditions they please upon the vanquished.
{Quote_10}
Varus, give me back my legions.
{Quote_11}
Let them hate us as long as they fear us.
{Quote_12}
The sinews of war are infinite money.
{Quote_13}
Armed forces abroad are of little value unless there is prudent counsel at home.
{Quote_14}
Only the brave enjoy noble and glorious deaths.
{Quote_15}
To an imperial city nothing is inconsistent which is expedient.
{Quote_16}
The true contempt of an invader is shown by deeds of valour in the field.
{Quote_17}
When there is mutual fear men think twice before they make aggression upon one another.
{Quote_18}
They have an abundance of gold and silver, and these make war, like other things, go smoothly.
{Quote_19}
Nobody is driven in to war by ignorance, and no one who thinks he will gain anything from it is deterred by fear.
{Quote_20}
In peace, sons bury their fathers; in war, fathers bury their sons.
{Quote_21}
Far better it is to have a stout heart always and suffer one's share of evils, than to be ever fearing what may happen.
{Quote_22}
Men of Athens, there is not much time for exhortation, but to the brave a few words are as good as many.
{Quote_23}
War is the only proper school of the surgeon.
{Quote_24}
Even the bravest cannot fight beyond his strength.
{Quote_25}
Ye gods, what dastards would our host command? Swept to the war, the lumber of the land.
{Quote_26}
Noble and manly music invigorates the spirit, strengthens the wavering man, and incites him to great and worthy deeds.
{Quote_27}
He serves me most, who serves his country best.
{Quote_29}
To those that flee comes neither power nor glory.
{Quote_30}
Adversity reveals the genius of a general; good fortune conceals it.
{Quote_31}
A wise man in times of peace prepares for war.
{Quote_32}
To a good general luck is important.
{Quote_33}
The outcome corresponds less to expectations in war than in any other case whatsoever.
{Quote_34}
It is pleasant, when the sea is high and the winds are dashing the waves about, to watch from the shores the struggles of another.
{Quote_35}
To brave men, the prizes that war offers are liberty and fame.
{Quote_36}
The man who runs away will fight again.
{Quote_37}
A small country cannot contend with a great; the few cannot contend with the many; the weak cannot contend with the strong.
{Quote_38}
Soldiers do not like being under the command of one who is not of noble birth.
{Quote_39}
To blunder twice is not allowed in war.
{Quote_40}
I am more afraid of our own mistakes than of our enemies' designs.
{Quote_41}
He conquers who endures.
{Quote_42}
After the war is over, make alliances.
{Quote_43}
An alliance with the powerful is never to be trusted.
{Quote_44}
In the moment of action remember the value of silence and order.
{Quote_45}
A large army is always disorderly.
{Quote_46}
The rulers of the States are the only ones who should have the privilege of lying.
{Quote_47}
Every care must be taken that our auxiliaries, being stronger than our citizens, may not grow too much for them and become savage beasts.
{Quote_48}
Conquered, we conquer.
{Quote_49}
Ah, yes, mere infantry - poor beggars...
{Quote_50}
The valiant profit more their country than the finest, cleverest speakers.
{Quote_51}
Hannibal knew how to gain a victory, but not how to use it.
{Quote_52}
Extraordinary rains pretty generally fall after great battles.
{Quote_53}
A good general not only sees the way to victory, he also knows when victory is impossible.
{Quote_54}
In war we must always leave room for strokes of fortune, and accidents that cannot be foreseen.
{Quote_55}
Pardon one offence and you encourage the commission of many.
{Quote_56}
We should provide in peace what we need in war.
{Quote_57}
Necessity knows no law except to conquer.
{Quote_58}
It is a bad plan that cannot be altered.
{Quote_59}
He is best secure from dangers who is on his guard even when he seems safe.
{Quote_60}
If a man does not know to what port he is sailing, no wind is favourable.
{Quote_61}
In war we must be speedy.
{Quote_62}
A disorderly mob is no more an army than a heap of building materials is a house.
{Quote_63}
Quick decisions are unsafe decisions.
{Quote_64}
The cruelty of war makes for peace.
{Quote_65}
Great empires are not maintained by timidity.
{Quote_66}
Even the bravest are frightened by sudden terrors.
{Quote_67}
The proper arts of a general are judgement and prudence.
{Quote_68}
A bad peace is even worse than war.
{Quote_69}
The desire for safety stands against every great and noble enterprise.
{Quote_70}
War is not so much a matter of weapons as of money.
{Quote_71}
An ambush, if discovered and promptly surrounded, will repay the intended mischief with interest.
{Quote_72}
Few men are born brave; many become so through training and force of discipline.
{Quote_73}
A general is not easily overcome who can form a true judgement of his own and the enemy's forces.
{Quote_74}
What can a soldier do who charges when out of breath?
{Quote_75}
Victory loves prudence.
{Quote_76}
A dead enemy always smells good.
{Quote_77}
When one side goes against the enemy with the gods' gift of stronger morale, then their adversaries, as a rule, cannot withstand them.
{Author_1}
Aeschylus
{Author_2}
Aeschylus
{Author_3}
Latin proverb
{Author_4}
Aesop
{Author_5}
Alcaeus
{Author_6}
Archidamus of Sparta
{Author_7}
Aristophanes
{Author_8}
Aristotle
{Author_9}
Julius Caesar
{Author_10}
Augustus Caesar : After the defeat and annihilation of Varus' column in Teutoberg Forest
{Author_11}
Caligula
{Author_12}
Cicero
{Author_13}
Cicero
{Author_14}
Dionysius
{Author_15}
Euphemus of Athens
{Author_16}
Hermocrates of Syracuse
{Author_17}
Hermocrates of Syracuse
{Author_18}
Hermocrates of Syracuse
{Author_19}
Hermocrates of Syracuse
{Author_20}
Herodotus
{Author_21}
Herodotus
{Author_22}
Hippocrates
{Author_23}
Hippocrates
{Author_24}
Homer
{Author_25}
Homer
{Author_26}
Homer
{Author_27}
Homer
{Author_29}
Homer
{Author_30}
Horace
{Author_31}
Horace
{Author_32}
Livy
{Author_33}
Livy
{Author_34}
Lucretius
{Author_35}
Lycurgus of Sparta
{Author_36}
Menander
{Author_37}
Mencius
{Author_38}
Onosander
{Author_39}
Latin proverb
{Author_40}
Pericles
{Author_41}
Persius
{Author_42}
Greek proverb
{Author_43}
Phaedrus
{Author_44}
Phormio of Athens
{Author_45}
Euripides
{Author_46}
Plato
{Author_47}
Plato
{Author_48}
Plautus
{Author_49}
Plautus
{Author_50}
Plautus
{Author_51}
Maharbal
{Author_52}
Plutarch
{Author_53}
Polybius
{Author_54}
Polybius
{Author_55}
Publilius Syrus
{Author_56}
Publilius Syrus
{Author_57}
Publilius Syrus
{Author_58}
Publilius Syrus
{Author_59}
Publilius Syrus
{Author_60}
Seneca
{Author_61}
Silius Italicus
{Author_62}
Socrates
{Author_63}
Sophocles
{Author_64}
Publius Statius
{Author_65}
Tacitus
{Author_66}
Tacitus
{Author_67}
Tacitus
{Author_68}
Tacitus
{Author_69}
Tacitus
{Author_70}
Thucydides
{Author_71}
Vegetius
{Author_72}
Vegetius
{Author_73}
Vegetius
{Author_74}
Vegetius
{Author_75}
Latin proverb
{Author_76}
Alus Vitellus
{Author_77}
Xenophon
{quote_78}
Only the dead have seen the end of the war.
{quoted_79}
Plato
{quote_80}
Veni, vidi, vici
{trans_81}
I came, I saw, I conquered.
{quoted_82}
Gaius Julius Caesar
{quote_83}
Silent enim leges inter arma
{trans_84}
Laws are silent in times of war.
{quoted_85}
Cicero
{quote_86}
We make war that we may live in peace.
{quoted_87}
Aristotle
{quote_88}
Men grow tired of sleep, love, singing and dancing sooner than war.
{quoted_89}
Homer
{quote_90}
War spares not the brave but the cowardly.
{quoted_91}
Anacreon
{quote_92}
War is sweet to those who have never experienced it.
{quoted_93}
Pindar
{quote_94}
In war important events result from trivial causes.
{quoted_95}
Gaius Julius Caesar
{quote_96}
Bella detesta matribus
{trans_97}
Wars are the dread of mothers.
{quoted_98}
Horace
{quote_99}
Bella, horida bella
{trans_100}
Wars, horrid wars!
{quoted_101}
Virgil
{quote_102}
Willing obedience always beats forced obedience.
{quoted_103}
Xenophon
{quote_104}
The fortunes of war are always doubtful.
{quoted_105}
Seneca
{quote_106}
The Spartans do not ask how many but where they are.
{quoted_107}
Agis II of Sparta
{quote_108}
Come home with this shield or upon it.
{quoted_109}
A Spartan woman equips her son
{quote_110}
Valour is superior to numbers.
{quoted_111}
Vegetius
{quote_112}
Valour is the contempt of death and pain.
{quoted_113}
Tacitus
{quote_114}
To lead untrained people to war is to throw them away.
{quoted_115}
Confucius
{quote_116}
In war, truth is the first casualty.
{quoted_117}
Aeschylus
{quote_118}
Dulce et decorum est pro patria mori
{trans_119}
It is a sweet and seemly thing to die for one's country.
{quoted_120}
Horace
{quote_121}
Qui desiderat pacem praeparet bellum
{trans_122}
Let him who desires peace prepare for war.
{quoted_123}
Vegetius
{quote_124}
An ambuscade, if discovered and promptly surrounded, will repay the intended mischief with interest.
{quoted_125}
Vegetius
{quote_126}
The blade itself incites to violence.
{quoted_127}
Homer
{quote_128}
Who was the first that forged the deadly blade? Of rugged steel his savage soul was made.
{quoted_129}
Tibullus
{quote_130}
So ends the bloody business of the day.
{quoted_131}
Homer
{quote_132}
Quae caret ora cruore nostro?
{trans_133}
What coast knows not our blood?
{quoted_134}
Horace
{quote_135}
Arms keep peace.
{quoted_136}
Latin proverb
{quote_137}
The gods favour the bold.
{quoted_138}
Ovid
{quote_139}
Great empires are not maintained by timidity.
{quoted_140}
Tacitus
{quote_141}
Fortes fortuna adiuvat
{trans_142}
Fortune favours the brave.
{quoted_143}
Terence
{quote_144}
Only the brave enjoy noble and glorious deaths.
{quoted_145}
Dionysius of Halicarnassus
{quote_146}
Few men are born brave; many become so through training and force of discipline.
{quoted_147}
Vegetius
{quote_148}
Fortis cadere, cedere non potest
{trans_149}
A brave man may fall, but he cannot yield.
{quoted_150}
Latin proverb
{quote_151}
In peace, sons bury their fathers; in war, fathers bury their sons.
{quoted_152}
Herodotus
{quote_153}
How are the mighty fallen in the midst of battle!
{quoted_154}
II Samuel, I, 25
{quote_155}
The walls shall shake at the noise of the horsemen, and of the wheels, and of the chariots.
{quoted_156}
Ezekiel, XXVI, 10
{quote_157}
Alta sedent civilis vulnera dextrae
{trans_158}
Deep are the wounds that civil strife inflicts.
{quoted_159}
Lucan
{quote_160}
A collision at sea can ruin your entire day.
{quoted_161}
Thucydides
{quote_162}
Fas est et ab hoste doceri
{trans_163}
It is right to learn, even from the enemy.
{quoted_164}
Ovid
{quote_165}
Learn to obey before you command.
{quoted_166}
Solon of Athens
{quote_167}
March divided and fight concentrated.
{quoted_168}
Military maxim
{quote_169}
Divide et impera
{trans_169}
Divide and conquer.
{quoted_170}
Military maxim
{quote_171}
Victi vincimus
{trans_172}
Conquered, we conquer.
{quoted_173}
Plautus
{quote_174}
Flet victus, victor interiit
{trans_175}
The conquered mourns, the conqueror is undone.
{quoted_176}
Latin proverb
{quote_177}
Courage may be taught as a child is taught to speak.
{quoted_178}
Euripides
{quote_179}
Timidi mater non flet
{trans_180}
A coward's mother does not weep.
{quoted_181}
Latin proverb
{quote_182}
Danger gleams like sunshine to a brave man's eyes.
{quoted_183}
Euripides
{quote_184}
Constant exposure to dangers will breed contempt for them.
{quoted_185}
Seneca
{quote_186}
A glorious death is his who for his country falls.
{quoted_187}
Homer
{quote_188}
All warfare is based on deception.
{quoted_189}
Sun Tzu
{quote_190}
The god of war hates those who hesitate.
{quoted_191}
Euripides
{quote_192}
Alea iacta est
{trans_193}
The die is cast.
{quoted_194}
Gaius Julius Caesar
{quote_195}
Vae victus
{trans_196}
Woe to the vanquished.
{quoted_197}
Livy
{quote_198}
Let all be present and expect the palm, the prize of victory.
{quoted_199}
Virgil
{quote_200}
Brave men are a city's strongest tower of defence.
{quoted_201}
Alcaeus
{quote_202}
The true contempt of an invader is shown by deeds of valour in the field.
{quoted_203}
Hermocrates of Syracuse
{quote_204}
An adversary is more hurt by desertion than by slaughter.
{quoted_205}
Vegetius
{quote_206}
Self-control is the chief element in self-respect, and self-respect is the chief element in courage.
{quoted_207}
Thucydides
{quote_208}
Cry "Havoc!" and let slip the dogs of war.
{quoted_209}
Shakespeare: Julius Caesar, III, 1
{quote_210}
The strong did what they could, and the weak suffered what they must.
{quoted_211}
Thucydides
{quote_212}
The sinews of war are infinite money.
{quoted_213}
Cicero
{quote_214}
He who knows when he can fight and when he cannot will be victorious.
{quoted_215}
Sun Tzu
{quote_216}
The proper arts of a general are judgement and prudence.
{quoted_217}
Tacitus
{quote_218}
It is the brave man's part to live with glory, or with glory die.
{quoted_219}
Sophocles
{quote_220}
We should provide in peace what we need in war.
{quoted_221}
Publilius Syrus
{quote_222}
Generally management of the many is the same as management of the few. It is a matter of organization.
{quoted_223}
Sun Tzu
{quote_224}
If a man does not strike first, he will be the first struck.
{quoted_225}
Athenogoras of Syracuse
{quote_226}
A wise man in times of peace prepares for war.
{quoted_227}
Horace
{quote_228}
In war, numbers alone confer no advantage. Do not advance relying on sheer military power.
{quoted_229}
Sun Tzu




{new_quote_1}
Even a fool learns something once it hits him.
{new_quoted_1}
Homer
{new_quote_2}
Giraffes are heartless creatures.
{new_quoted_2}

{new_quote_3}
Famous men have the whole earth as their memorial.
{new_quoted_3}
Pericles
{new_quote_4}
Another thing that has escaped your notice, Gisgo, is even more amazing:
{new_trans_4}
That, although there are so many of them, there is not one among them called Gisgo.
{new_quoted_4}
Hannibal, to a soldier noting the great size of the Roman army at Canae
{new_quote_5}
Every kingdom divided against itself is brought to desolation;
{new_trans_5}
and every city or house divided against itself shall not stand.
{new_quoted_5}
Matthew, XII, 25
{new_quote_6}
I, against my brothers. I and my brothers, against my cousins.
{new_trans_6}
I, and my brothers, and my cousins, against the world.
{new_quoted_6}
Bedouin proverb
{new_quote_7}
Vae victis!
{new_trans_7}
Woe to the vanquished!
{new_quoted_7}
Brennus of the Senones
{new_quote_8}
Non auro, sed ferro, recuperanda est patria
{new_trans_8}
Not with gold, but with iron we must recover the country.
{new_quoted_8}
Marcus Furius Camillus




{Alex_Quote_1}
I do not separate people, as do the narrow-minded, into Greeks and barbarians.
{Alex_Author_1}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_2}
For me each good foreigner is a Greek and each bad Greek is worse than a barbarian.
{Alex_Author_2}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_3}
I would rather live a short life of glory than a long one of obscurity.
{Alex_Author_3}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_4}
How great are the dangers I face to win a good name in Athens.
{Alex_Author_4}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_5}
I am dying from the treatment of too many physicians.
{Alex_Author_5}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_6}
I would rather excel others in the knowledge of what is excellent than in the extent of my powers and dominion.
{Alex_Author_6}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_7}
In faith and hope the world will disagree, But all mankind's concern is charity.
{Alex_Author_7}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_8}
Remember upon the conduct of each depends the fate of all.
{Alex_Author_8}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_9}
There is nothing impossible to him who will try.
{Alex_Author_9}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_10}
I am indebted to my father for living, but to my teacher for living well.
{Alex_Author_10}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_11}
Is it not worthy of tears that, when the number of worlds is infinite, we have not yet become lords of a single one?
{Alex_Author_11}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_12}
Heaven cannot brook two suns, nor earth two masters.
{Alex_Author_12}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_13}
I send you a kaffis of mustard seed, that you may taste and acknowledge the bitterness of my victory.
{Alex_Author_13}
Alexander in a letter to King Darius III of Persia
{Alex_Quote_14}
When Alexander saw the breadth of his domain, he wept for there were no more worlds to conquer.
{Alex_Author_14}
Source unknown
{Alex_Quote_15}
Sex and sleep alone make me conscious that I am mortal.
{Alex_Author_15}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_16}
The end and perfection of our victories is to avoid the vices and infirmities of those whom we subdue.
{Alex_Author_16}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_17}
If I were not Alexander, then I should wish to be Diogenes.
{Alex_Author_17}
Alexander when asked to stand out of the philosopher Diogenes' sunshine.
{Alex_Quote_18}
O fortunate youth, to have found Homer as the herald of your glory!
{Alex_Author_18}
Alexander the Great on visiting Achilles' tomb
{Alex_Quote_19}
Alexander was a descendant of Heracles and...the Aeacids, so that...he inherited the physical and moral qualities of greatness.
{Alex_Author_19}
Diodoros of Sicily
{Alex_Quote_20}
Alexander observed that his soldiers were exhausted with their constant campaigns...The hooves of the horses had been worn thin by steady marching.
{Alex_Author_20}
Diodoros of Sicily
{Alex_Quote_21}
Your ancestors invaded Macedonia and the rest of Greece and did us great harm, though we had done them no prior injury.
{Alex_Author_21}
Alexander in a letter to King Darius III of Persia
{Alex_Quote_22}
Alexander son of Philip and the Hellenes...set up these spoils from the barbarians dwelling in Asia.
{Alex_Author_22}
Inscription on spoils sent by Alexander to Athens
{Alex_Quote_23}
The book of Daniel...declared that one of the Greeks should destroy the empire of the Persians, (Alexander) supposed that himself was the person intended.
{Alex_Author_23}
Flavius Josephus
{Alex_Quote_24}
We know how weak their power is; already have we subdued their children who dwell in our country.
{Alex_Author_24}
The Persian general Mardonius on the Greeks
{Alex_Quote_25}
The Greeks are accustomed to wage wars...Since they speak the same language, they should end their disputes.
{Alex_Author_25}
The Persian general Mardonius on the Greeks
{Alex_Quote_26}
I do not fear an army of lions, if they are led by a lamb. I do fear an army of sheep, if they are led by a lion.
{Alex_Author_26}
Philip II of Macedon
{Alex_Quote_27}
True love never has a happy ending, that is because true love never has an ending.
{Alex_Author_27}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_28}
Great deeds are usually wrought at great risks. 
{Alex_Author_28}
Herodotus
{Alex_Quote_29}
Our characters are the result of our conduct.
{Alex_Author_29}
Aristotle
{Alex_Quote_30}
We are what we repeatedly do.
{Alex_Author_30}
Aristotle
{Alex_Quote_31}
We make war that we may live in peace.
{Alex_Author_31}
Aristotle
{Alex_Quote_32}
It is the nature of desire not to be satisfied.
{Alex_Author_32}
Aristotle
{Alex_Quote_33}
I am not interested in the origin or race of citizens. I only distinguish them on the basis of their virtue.
{Alex_Author_33}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_34}
We live in deeds, not years.
{Alex_Author_34}
Aristotle
{Alex_Quote_35}
You will never do anything in this world without courage.
{Alex_Author_35}
Aristotle
{Alex_Quote_36}
Courage is the greatest quality of the mind next to honor.
{Alex_Author_36}
Aristotle
{Alex_Quote_37}
O my son, seek out a kingdom worthy of thyself, for Macedonia is too little for thee.
{Alex_Author_37}
Philip II of Macedon
{Alex_Quote_38}
My father will get ahead of me in everything, and will leave nothing great for me to do.
{Alex_Author_38}
Alexander as a youth
{Alex_Quote_39}
Never mind, mother.  He's Alexander, too.
{Alex_Author_39}
Alexander to Darius' captured mother after she mistook his lover Hephaistion for him.
{Alex_Quote_40}
Alexander fought many battles, and took of the strongholds of all, and slew the kings of the earth.
{Alex_Author_40}
I Maccabees, I, 2
{Alex_Quote_41}
(Alexander) went through even to the ends of the earth, and took the spoils of many nations: and the earth was quiet before him.
{Alex_Author_41}
I Maccabees, I, 3
{Alex_Quote_42}
(Alexander) gathered a power and a very strong army; and his heart was exalted and lifted up.
{Alex_Author_42}
I Maccabees, I 4
{Alex_Quote_43}
And (Alexander)...subdued countries of nations, and princes; and they became tributary to him
{Alex_Author_43}
I Maccabees, I, 5
{Alex_Quote_44}
When invading an enemy's territory, men should always be confident in spirit, but they should fear, too, and take measures of precaution.
{Alex_Author_44}
Archidamus of Sparta
{Alex_Quote_45}
To brave men, the prizes that war offers are liberty and fame.
{Alex_Author_45}
Lycurgus of Sparta
{Alex_Quote_46}
The horseman lifteth up both the bright sword and the glittering spear: there is a multitude of slain, and a great number of carcasses; and there is none end of their corpses; they stumble upon their corpses.
{Alex_Author_46}
Nahum, III, 3
{Alex_Quote_47}
Happy the warrior to whom comes joy of battle.
{Alex_Author_47}
Bhagavad-Gita
{Alex_Quote_48}
In the moment of action remember the value of silence and order.
{Alex_Author_48}
Phormio of Athens
{Alex_Quote_49}
There is not much time for exhortation, but to the brave a few words are as good as many.
{Alex_Author_49}
Hippocrates of Athens
{Alex_Quote_50}
The world belongs to the brave.
{Alex_Author_50}
Proverb
{Alex_Quote_51}
Their horses are swifter than the leopards, and are more fierce than the evening wolves.
{Alex_Author_51}
Habakkuk, I, 8
{Alex_Quote_52}
And their horsemen shall come from afar; they shall fly as the eagle that hasteth to eat.
{Alex_Author_52}
Habakkuk, I, 8
{Alex_Quote_53}
No one has ever died in battle through being bitten...by a horse. It is men who do whatever gets done in battle.
{Alex_Author_53}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_54}
The conquered are destroyed by, and the conquerors destroy, their friends.
{Alex_Author_54}
Dionysius of Halicarnassus
{Alex_Quote_55}
Learn to obey before you command.
{Alex_Author_55}
Solon of Athens
{Alex_Quote_56}
More of those who shrink from shame are safe than fall in battle, while with those who flee is neither glory nor reprieve from death.
{Alex_Author_56}
Homer
{Alex_Quote_57}
O strong of heart, go where the road of ancient honor climbs. Bow not your craven shoulders. Earth conquered gives the stars.
{Alex_Author_57}
Boethius
{Alex_Quote_58}
Cowards do not count in battle; they are there but not in it.
{Alex_Author_58}
Euripides
{Alex_Quote_59}
Danger gleams like sunshine to a brave man's eyes.
{Alex_Author_59}
Euripides
{Alex_Quote_60}
The god of war hates those who hesitate.
{Alex_Author_60}
Euripides
{Alex_Quote_61}
The strength of an army lies in strict discipline and undeviating obedience to its officers.
{Alex_Author_61}
Thucydides
{Alex_Quote_62}
Lack of discipline has destroyed many people before now.
{Alex_Author_62}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_63}
A small army consisting of chosen troops is far better than a vast body chiefly composed of rabble.
{Alex_Author_63}
The Hitopadesa
{Alex_Quote_64}
War is not so much a matter of weapons as of money, for money furnishes the material for war.
{Alex_Author_64}
Thucydides
{Alex_Quote_65}
Fight with silver spears and you will conquer everywhere.
{Alex_Author_65}
The Oracle at Delphi to Philip II of Macedon
{Alex_Quote_66}
A general in the field should endeavour to discover in the chief that is against him, whether there be any weakness in his mind or character, through which he may be attacked with some advantage.
{Alex_Author_66}
Polybius
{Alex_Quote_67}
(A general) must be observant, untiring, shrewd, kindly and cruel, simple and crafty, a watchman and a robber...rash and conservative.
{Alex_Author_67}
Socrates
{Alex_Quote_68}
Glory is a mighty spur.
{Alex_Author_68}
Ovid
{Alex_Quote_69}
It is the brave man's part to live with glory, or with glory die.
{Alex_Author_69}
Sophocles
{Alex_Quote_70}
The god of war hates those who hesitate.
{Alex_Author_70}
Euripides
{Alex_Quote_71}
When dangers are great, there the greatest honors are to be won by men and states.
{Alex_Author_71}
Thucydides
{Alex_Quote_72}
(The leader) must be ready to suffer more hardships than he asks of his soldiers, more fatigue, greater extremes of heat and cold.
{Alex_Author_72}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_73}
Maintain discipline and caution above all things, and be on the alert to obey the word of command.
{Alex_Author_73}
Archidamus of Sparta
{Alex_Quote_74}
Make war support war.
{Alex_Author_74}
Military maxim
{Alex_Quote_75}
It is not numbers or strength that bring victories in war.
{Alex_Author_75}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_76}
Willing obedience always beats forced obedience.
{Alex_Author_76}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_77}
The minds of men are apt to be swayed by what they hear; and they are most afraid of those who commence an attack.
{Alex_Author_77}
Hermocrates of Syracuse
{Alex_Quote_78}
No one can be a good officer who does not undergo more than those he commands.
{Alex_Author_78}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_79}
The barbarians were instantly seized by one of those unaccountable great panics to which great armies are liable.
{Alex_Author_79}
Thucydides
{Alex_Quote_80}
Let our axes crush cloth and bones as the jaws of the hyena crush its prey. Make the wounds we give to gape.
{Alex_Author_80}
Hindu prayer to the war god, Loha Pennu
{Alex_Quote_81}
Reinforcements are always more formidable to an enemy than the troops with which he is already engaged.
{Alex_Author_81}
Brasidas of Sparta
{Alex_Quote_82}
They ran away from the word of dishonor but on the field of battle their feet stood fast.
{Alex_Author_82}
Pericles
{Alex_Quote_83}
Men would rather have their fill of sleep, love, singing and dancing, than of war.
{Alex_Author_83}
Homer
{Alex_Quote_84}
To them that fleeth cometh neither power nor glory.
{Alex_Author_84}
Homer
{Alex_Quote_85}
Safety lies forward.
{Alex_Author_85}
Military maxim
{Alex_Quote_86}
He was fond of adventure, ready to lead an attack on the enemy by day or night, and, when he was in an awkward position, he kept his head.
{Alex_Author_86}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_87}
It is a high thing, a bright honor, for a man to do battle with the enemy...death is a thing that will come when the spinning Destinies make it come.
{Alex_Author_87}
Grecian lyric, 4th century BC
{Alex_Quote_88}
Readiness, obedience, and a sense of humour are the virtues of a soldier.
{Alex_Author_88}
Brasidas of Sparta
{Alex_Quote_89}
Even the bravest cannot fight beyond his strength.
{Alex_Author_89}
Homer
{Alex_Quote_90}
And so it is certain that a small country cannot contend with a great, that few cannot contend with many.
{Alex_Author_90}
Mencius
{Alex_Quote_91}
The execution of a military surprise is always dangerous.
{Alex_Author_91}
Thucydides
{Alex_Quote_92}
The general who is never taken off his guard himself, and never loses an opportunity of striking at an unguarded foe, will be most likely to succeed in war.
{Alex_Author_92}
Thucydides
{Alex_Quote_93}
He is best who is trained in the severest school.
{Alex_Author_93}
Thucydides
{Alex_Quote_94}
Whoever wants to keep alive must aim at victory. It is the winners who do the killing and the losers who get killed.
{Alex_Author_94}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_95}
The art of war is, in the last result, the art of keeping one's freedom of action.
{Alex_Author_95}
Xenophon
{Alex_Quote_96}
Let us carefully observe those good qualities wherein our enemies excel us; and endeavor to excel them, by avoiding what is faulty, and imitating what is excellent in them. 
{Alex_Author_96}
Plutarch
{Alex_Quote_97}
To be ignorant of the lives of the most celebrated men of antiquity is to continue in a state of childhood all our days. 
{Alex_Author_97} 
Plutarch
{Alex_Quote_98}
A few vices are sufficient to darken many virtues. 
{Alex_Author_98}
Plutarch
{Alex_Quote_99}
Courage stands half way between cowardice and rashness, one of which is a lack, the other an excess of courage.
{Alex_Author_99}
Plutarch
{Alex_Quote_100}
This, however, was said distinctly in words by the prophet to the king — that he, Alexander, was the son of Zeus.
{Alex_Author_100}
Callisthenes
{Alex_Quote_101}
All mortals from now on will live like one people, united, and peacefully working towards a common prosperity. 
{Alex_Author_101}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_102}
You should regard the whole world as your own country with common laws, a country where the best and the brightest rule, regardless of race.
{Alex_Author_102}
Alexander the Great
{Alex_Quote_103}
Great deeds are usually wrought at great risks. 
{Alex_Author_103}
Herodotus
{Alex_Quote_104}
All men's gains are the fruit of venturing.
{Alex_Author_104}
Herodotus
{Alex_Quote_105}
'Twas at the royal feast, for Persia won by Philip's warlike son: aloft, in awful state, the godlike hero sate on his imperial throne. 
{Alex_Author_105}
Dryden
{Alex_Quote_106}
Many a night did he spend without sleeping, many a blood-stained day did he pass amid combats unceasing.
{Alex_Author_106}
Plutarch
{Alex_Quote_107}
All Macedonia was festering with revolt...  Persian gold flowed freely...everywhere, and helped to rouse the Peloponnesus.
{Alex_Author_107}
Plutarch
{Alex_Quote_108}
(Alexander's) true equipment was philosophic teaching, and treatises on Fearlessness and Courage, and Self-restraint also, and Greatness of Soul.
{Alex_Author_108}
Plutarch
{Alex_Quote_109}
In the case of Alexander...behold his body gashed with wounds tip to toe, bruised all over, smitten at the hands of his enemies.
{Alex_Author_109}
Plutarch
